<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Hexo</title>
  
  
  <link href="http://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://example.com/"/>
  <updated>2024-12-14T08:25:45.156Z</updated>
  <id>http://example.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>John Doe</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Face Recognition</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/12/14/Face-Recognition/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/12/14/Face-Recognition/</id>
    <published>2024-12-14T08:24:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-12-14T08:25:45.156Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Face-Recognition"><a href="#Face-Recognition" class="headerlink" title="Face Recognition"></a>Face Recognition</h1><p>Face Recognition was part of the Human-Robot Interaction and my graduation project, which is to build a reception robot. In a home environment, smart home robots must accurately detect and identify all family members to perform tasks specific to individual household members. Therefore, this chapter focuses on implementing facial recognition and analyzing related aspects.</p><p>Facial recognition tasks can be broadly divided into two parts: <strong>face detection</strong> and <strong>face recognition</strong>. Face detection refers to locating all faces in an input image and processing them, such as aligning the faces, generating bounding boxes, and resizing or cropping the detected faces. However, due to the potential challenges posed by the robot’s field of vision, such as incomplete or peripheral facial appearances, face detection can become more complex. Additional complications arise from variations in lighting, occlusions, differences in the same individual’s pose or expressions, and inter-individual appearance differences.</p><p>To address these challenges, accurate facial recognition in complex environments requires precise localization of faces, followed by the detection of facial feature points, such as facial contours, eye outlines, nose, and mouth contours. These feature points are then used to align the faces uniformly, eliminating errors caused by position or pose variations.</p><p><strong>Face recognition</strong> can be described as comparing a given photo to a dataset, calculating the facial similarity, and outputting a similarity score or confidence level. Alternatively, it involves identifying which individual in the dataset the photo belongs to and retrieving the relevant information about the individual from the database.</p><p>A representative algorithm in this domain is <strong>FaceNet</strong>, which won the 2014 ILSVRC (ImageNet Large Scale Visual Recognition Challenge) and reduced the Top-5 error rate for facial recognition to 6.67%. FaceNet uses the GoogLeNet network architecture, as outlined in the associated paper [21]. Following this milestone, facial recognition algorithms have continued to evolve. The latest implementation on GitHub recommends using the <strong>MTCNN</strong> (Multi-task Cascaded Convolutional Networks) algorithm [22], which improves detection accuracy to 99.65%.</p><p>Therefore, the primary focus of this chapter is the introduction and implementation of the MTCNN and FaceNet network architectures.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;Face-Recognition&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Face-Recognition&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Face Recognition&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Face Recognition&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Face Recogniti</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Robotics" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Robotics/"/>
    
    <category term="HCI" scheme="http://example.com/tags/HCI/"/>
    
    <category term="CNN" scheme="http://example.com/tags/CNN/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>My first cv project, from ID card to face recognition</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/12/12/My-first-university-project-from-ID-card-to-KYC/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/12/12/My-first-university-project-from-ID-card-to-KYC/</id>
    <published>2024-12-12T03:29:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-12-14T08:25:22.960Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="My-first-cv-project-Extract-ID-card-number"><a href="#My-first-cv-project-Extract-ID-card-number" class="headerlink" title="My first cv project: Extract ID card number"></a>My first cv project: Extract ID card number</h1><p>My CV story starts with a cousrse project when I was in sophomore. The final personal project can be selected from the following choices: 24-point game program, Tetris, ID card number extraction, face recognition by opencv, License plate number extraction. Actually, I have finished the first two in other courses and face recognition(CNN, will be introduced in the following part) was my parallel project directed by another professor, so only two choices:  ID card number extraction or License plate number extraction. They were same to me, so I chose ID card number extraction. </p><p>Let’s start!</p><h2 id="Development-Process"><a href="#Development-Process" class="headerlink" title="Development Process"></a>Development Process</h2><h3 id="Step-1-Development-Environment"><a href="#Step-1-Development-Environment" class="headerlink" title="Step 1: Development Environment"></a>Step 1: Development Environment</h3><p>The project uses:</p><ul><li><strong>OpenCV</strong>: A library for working with images.</li><li><strong>NumPy</strong>: For numerical operations like creating matrices.</li><li><strong>Pytesseract</strong>: A library to perform OCR (Optical Character Recognition) to extract text from images.</li></ul><h3 id="Step-2-Loading-the-Image"><a href="#Step-2-Loading-the-Image" class="headerlink" title="Step 2: Loading the Image"></a>Step 2: Loading the Image</h3><p><code>image = cv2.imread(&#39;test1.jpg&#39;)</code></p><p>test1.jpg will be the ID card, which is from the Internet.</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://allenzhuer.github.io/picx-images-hosting/image.m4lbulzo.webp"                      alt="image"                ></p><h3 id="Step-3-Finding-the-Area-with-the-ID-Number-Region-of-Interest"><a href="#Step-3-Finding-the-Area-with-the-ID-Number-Region-of-Interest" class="headerlink" title="Step 3: Finding the Area with the ID Number (Region of Interest)"></a>Step 3: Finding the Area with the ID Number (Region of Interest)</h3><p><code>height, width = image.shape[:2] roi = image[int(0.75 * height):height, int(0.1 * width):int(0.9 * width)]</code> The program crops the bottom part of the image, where the ID number is expected. It assumes the ID number is located in a specific area (e.g., the bottom center of the image). </p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://allenzhuer.github.io/picx-images-hosting/image.8ojr0exryr.webp"                      alt="image"                ></p><h3 id="Step-4-Cleaning-the-Image"><a href="#Step-4-Cleaning-the-Image" class="headerlink" title="Step 4: Cleaning the Image"></a>Step 4: Cleaning the Image</h3><p>Before extracting text, the program prepares the image to make it easier for Tesseract to read.</p><ol><li><strong>Convert to Grayscale</strong>: Removes color, leaving only shades of gray.</li></ol><p><code>gray_image = cv2.cvtColor(roi, cv2.COLOR_BGR2GRAY)</code></p><ol start="2"><li><strong>Blur the Image</strong>: Reduces noise by smoothing the image.</li></ol><p><code>blurred_image = cv2.GaussianBlur(gray_image, (5, 5), 0)</code></p><ol start="3"><li><strong>Thresholding</strong>: Converts the image into pure black and white.</li></ol><p><code>_, thresholded_image = cv2.threshold(blurred_image, 0, 255, cv2.THRESH_BINARY + cv2.THRESH_OTSU)</code></p><ol start="4"><li><strong>Morphological Cleaning</strong>: Removes small imperfections (like dots or specks) in the image.</li></ol><p><code>kernel = np.ones((3, 3), np.uint8) cleaned_image = cv2.morphologyEx(thresholded_image, cv2.MORPH_CLOSE, kernel)</code></p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://allenzhuer.github.io/picx-images-hosting/image.4ckxsvk4lh.webp"                      alt="image"                ></p><h3 id="Step-5-Extracting-the-Text"><a href="#Step-5-Extracting-the-Text" class="headerlink" title="Step 5: Extracting the Text"></a>Step 5: Extracting the Text</h3><p><code>extracted_text = pytesseract.image_to_string(cleaned_image, config=custom_config)</code></p><p><strong>Tesseract OCR</strong> reads the cleaned image and tries to find text. And The <code>config</code> setting tells Tesseract to assume the text is in a single block and to use a specific engine mode.</p><h3 id="Step-6-Extracting-Only-Numbers"><a href="#Step-6-Extracting-Only-Numbers" class="headerlink" title="Step 6: Extracting Only Numbers"></a>Step 6: Extracting Only Numbers</h3><p><code>id_number = &#39;&#39;.join(filter(str.isdigit, extracted_text))</code></p><p>If the extracted text is too long, it tries to trim it to 18 digits (the typical length of a Chinese ID number).</p><h3 id="Step-7-Displaying-Results"><a href="#Step-7-Displaying-Results" class="headerlink" title="Step 7: Displaying Results"></a>Step 7: <strong>Displaying Results</strong></h3><p>Finally, the program displays the extracted number. If the result doesn’t look correct, it gives a warning. It also shows the intermediate images (like the cropped region and cleaned image) for debugging purposes.</p><p>The result will be “Extracted ID Number: 310109199107141011” which is the same as the ID number.</p><p>All done!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;My-first-cv-project-Extract-ID-card-number&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#My-first-cv-project-Extract-ID-card-number&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;My first</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Robotics" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Robotics/"/>
    
    <category term="opencv" scheme="http://example.com/tags/opencv/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The road to Navigation</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/12/12/The-road-to-Navigation/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/12/12/The-road-to-Navigation/</id>
    <published>2024-12-12T03:28:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-12-12T03:31:19.494Z</updated>
    
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Robotics" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Robotics/"/>
    
    <category term="Path Planning" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Path-Planning/"/>
    
    <category term="Navigation" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Navigation/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bridging Technology and Everyday Life, Building a Home Environment Reception Robot</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2024/11/25/Graduation-project-Mobile-robot-interaction-design-in-the-home-environment/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2024/11/25/Graduation-project-Mobile-robot-interaction-design-in-the-home-environment/</id>
    <published>2024-11-25T02:29:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-27T11:16:21.551Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h1><p>In an era where artificial intelligence and robotics are reshaping industries, the promise of home robots stands out as a beacon of innovation. Imagine a robot that can assist with household chores, recognize family members, engage in meaningful conversations, and adapt to dynamic environments. This vision inspired my graduation thesis, where I designed and implemented a mobile robot system tailored to interact seamlessly within a home environment. </p><p>A few years later, I learned that my project and work were used as teaching materials and the foundation for the teams from the School of Automation, Southeast University, to participate in the RoboCup@Home China. I’m very proud that my work can contribute to the competition. This also means my desire to dive deep into Human-Computer Interaction to combine cutting-edge technologies and business to create inspired products and services that solve customers’ problems.</p><blockquote><p>This is a list of the current desired technical abilities that the tests in RoboCup@Home will focus on.</p><ul><li>Navigation in dynamic environments </li><li>Fast and easy calibration and setup: The ultimate goal is to have a robot up and running out of the box</li><li>Object recognition </li><li>Object manipulation </li><li>Detection and Recognition of Humans </li><li>Natural human-robot interaction </li><li>Speech recognition </li><li>Gesture recognition </li><li>Robot applications RoboCup@Home is aiming for applications of robots in daily life.</li></ul></blockquote><p>This project aims to develop highly relevant service and assistive robot technology for future personal domestic applications. The focus lies on the following domains but is not limited to: Human-Robot Interaction and Cooperation, Navigation and Mapping in home environments, Computer Vision and Object Recognition under natural light conditions, Object Manipulation, Adaptive Behaviors, Standardization, and System Integration.</p><h1 id="Core-Functions"><a href="#Core-Functions" class="headerlink" title="Core Functions"></a>Core Functions</h1><h2 id="Scenario-Welcoming-Friends-at-Home-with-the-Robot-Assistant"><a href="#Scenario-Welcoming-Friends-at-Home-with-the-Robot-Assistant" class="headerlink" title="Scenario: Welcoming Friends at Home with the Robot Assistant"></a>Scenario: Welcoming Friends at Home with the Robot Assistant</h2><p>It’s a quiet afternoon at home, and you’ve invited a couple of friends over to relax and catch up. Just as you hear the doorbell ring, your robot assistant springs to life, ready to help create a seamless and welcoming experience.</p><h3 id="Step-1-Greeting-the-Guests"><a href="#Step-1-Greeting-the-Guests" class="headerlink" title="Step 1:  Greeting the Guests"></a>Step 1:  Greeting the Guests</h3><p>As your first friend steps into the house, the robot assistant moves forward to greet them. Its camera focuses on their face, and it says warmly:<br><em>“Hello, welcome! May I know your name?”</em><br>Your friend replies, “I’m Alex.” The robot repeats their name to confirm and then adds:<br><em>“It’s great to meet you, Alex. May I ask, what’s your favorite drink?”</em><br>Alex responds with a smile, “I love Cola.” The robot confirms their choice and saves their details, associating the name and drink preference with their face.</p><p>When your second friend arrives, the robot repeats the same process, efficiently recognizing and recording their name and drink preference as well.</p><p>If one of your friends is a frequent visitor, the robot has already  recognized them instantly then will greet them with personalized messages like:<br><em>“Welcome back, Alex! Would you like the usual Cola today?”</em> </p><h3 id="Step-2-Guiding-the-Guests-to-the-Living-Room"><a href="#Step-2-Guiding-the-Guests-to-the-Living-Room" class="headerlink" title="Step 2: Guiding the Guests to the Living Room"></a>Step 2: Guiding the Guests to the Living Room</h3><p>Once both friends are inside, the robot gestures and says:<br><em>“Please follow me, and I’ll guide you to your seats.”</em><br>It smoothly navigates through the house, leading your friends to the living room. It identifies the unoccupied seats and gestures politely:<br><em>“Here are two comfortable seats for you. Please, have a seat.”</em></p><h3 id="Step-3-Personalized-Drink-Delivery"><a href="#Step-3-Personalized-Drink-Delivery" class="headerlink" title="Step 3: Personalized Drink Delivery"></a>Step 3: Personalized Drink Delivery</h3><p>After your friends are seated, the robot turns to you for a moment and confirms:<br><em>“Would you like me to prepare the drinks for Alex and Jamie?”</em><br>You nod, and the robot replies, <em>“Understood. Please relax while I handle it.”</em></p><p>The robot moves to the kitchen, identifies the correct drinks, and carefully retrieves them. It returns to the living room and delivers the drinks to each guest by name:<br><em>“Alex, here’s your Cola. Jamie, here’s your favorite soda. Enjoy!”</em></p><p>Even if the robot can’t physically pick up the drinks, it uses a clear gesture or light indicator to direct your guests to their beverages, ensuring a thoughtful touch.</p><h3 id="Step-4-Creating-a-Relaxed-Atmosphere"><a href="#Step-4-Creating-a-Relaxed-Atmosphere" class="headerlink" title="Step 4: Creating a Relaxed Atmosphere"></a>Step 4: <strong>Creating a Relaxed Atmosphere</strong></h3><p>As the conversation flows, the robot subtly monitors the interaction, staying on standby in case anyone needs assistance. Its graphical user interface, displayed on a nearby screen, shows a friendly message such as:<br><em>“Let me know if you need anything else!”</em></p><p>If your friends move around, the robot adjusts and remains responsive, making sure they feel at home.</p><h2 id="Product-Function-and-Modules"><a href="#Product-Function-and-Modules" class="headerlink" title="Product Function and Modules"></a>Product Function and Modules</h2><p>The product’s core functionalities include the following five aspects:</p><ol><li><strong>Visitor Identification Based on Visual Recognition</strong>: Assuming there are two visitors, each arrives and pauses in front of the robot upon entry. The robot’s camera detects and captures their faces, automatically recognizes them, and saves the visitors’ facial images.</li><li><strong>Voice-Based Greeting Function</strong>: After detecting the visitor’s face, the robot provides a voice greeting and asks for the visitor’s name. It confirms the name by repetition and records it. The robot then asks for the visitor’s favorite beverage, confirms it, and records the information. Both the name and the preferred beverage are linked to the facial image, with the image file named after the visitor’s name.</li><li><strong>Seating Guidance Function</strong>: The robot directs the guest to an unoccupied seat. It issues a voice prompt, “Please follow me,” and leads the guest to the available spot, arranging for them to sit.</li><li><strong>Beverage Delivery Function</strong>: After the guest is seated, the robot moves to the beverage station, picks up the guest’s preferred drink (represented by an empty bottle if necessary), and delivers it to the correct guest. (If the grasping function is not feasible, the robot can instead point to the beverage.)</li><li><strong>Graphical User Interface Control</strong>: A graphical user interface is implemented to control the entire process.</li></ol><h4 id="Additional-Potential-Enhancements"><a href="#Additional-Potential-Enhancements" class="headerlink" title="Additional Potential Enhancements:"></a>Additional Potential Enhancements:</h4><ul><li>Adding object recognition to enable functionalities like object grasping and delivery.</li></ul><p>To meet the basic requirements, the product requires at least five functional modules: a camera detection module, a microphone acquisition module, a path planning module, a trajectory optimization module, and an arms control module. The correspondence between functions and modules is shown in <strong>Table 1</strong>.</p><h3 id="Table-1-Functions-and-Modules"><a href="#Table-1-Functions-and-Modules" class="headerlink" title="Table 1:  Functions and Modules"></a>Table 1:  Functions and Modules</h3><table><thead><tr><th>Function</th><th>Camera Detection Module</th><th>Microphone Acquisition Module</th><th>Path Planning Module</th><th>Trajectory Optimization Module</th><th>Arm Control Module</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Visitor identification based on face recognition</td><td>✓</td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Voice-based greeting function</td><td></td><td>✓</td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Seating guidance function</td><td>✓</td><td>✓</td><td>✓</td><td>✓</td><td></td></tr><tr><td>Beverage delivery and identification</td><td>✓</td><td></td><td></td><td>✓</td><td>✓</td></tr><tr><td>Graphical interface control</td><td>✓</td><td>✓</td><td>✓</td><td>✓</td><td>✓</td></tr></tbody></table><h1 id="Design-and-Methodology"><a href="#Design-and-Methodology" class="headerlink" title="Design and Methodology"></a>Design and Methodology</h1><h2 id="System-Overview"><a href="#System-Overview" class="headerlink" title="System Overview"></a>System Overview</h2><p>The system is built on a Turtlebot platform, enhanced with a HOKUYO URG-04LX-UG01 laser radar and an RGB-D camera for advanced functionality. Facial detection and recognition use MTCNN and FaceNet models, trained and fine-tuned on NVIDIA 2080Ti GPUs or Google Colab.</p><h4 id="Development-Environment"><a href="#Development-Environment" class="headerlink" title="Development Environment"></a><strong>Development Environment</strong></h4><ul><li><strong>OS</strong>: Ubuntu 16.04</li><li><strong>Frameworks</strong>: ROS for Turtlebot development, CUDA 9.0, and TensorFlow 1.7 for model training.</li></ul><h4 id="Final-Deployment"><a href="#Final-Deployment" class="headerlink" title="Final Deployment"></a><strong>Final Deployment</strong></h4><p>The fully developed system was successfully implemented on the MORO dual-arm robot, seamlessly integrating navigation, facial recognition, and robotic control. Since the MORO platform was still at the very beginning stage then, the grasp tasks were replaced by pointing to the drinks, and the KUKA LBR IIWA robot arm and RGBD camera realized the grasp tasks. </p><h2 id="Visitor-identification"><a href="#Visitor-identification" class="headerlink" title="Visitor identification"></a>Visitor identification</h2><p>The visitor identification task module primarily uses an <strong>RGB-D camera</strong> to actively capture images for face detection and recognition. The goal is to identify whether a detected face is new or already stored in the system database and transition seamlessly to the inquiry task once a face is recognized.</p><h4 id="Process-Flow"><a href="#Process-Flow" class="headerlink" title="Process Flow"></a><strong>Process Flow</strong></h4><ol><li><p><strong>Initialization</strong>:</p><ul><li>The robot begins in a stationary position at the door.</li><li>The <strong>camera thread</strong> is activated to continuously capture frames.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Face Detection</strong>:</p><ul><li>Each frame is analyzed for face detection with a time limit of <strong>3 seconds</strong> per detection attempt.</li><li>If no face is detected within 3 seconds, the robot performs <strong>small rotational movements</strong> to expand its field of view and continues detecting.</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Recognition and Database Check</strong>:</p><ul><li>If a face is detected:<ul><li>The system marks this recognition task as successful.</li><li>It checks the database for the detected face:<ul><li>If the face is new, the calculated facial feature data is extracted and stored in the database.</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Failure Handling</strong>:</p><ul><li><p>If no face is detected after </p><p>3 seconds of rotation</p><p>, the system:</p><ul><li>Confirms whether any face was found during the current session.</li><li>If no face was found:<ul><li>All threads are stopped, and the robot pauses operations for 3 seconds before restarting the recognition task.</li></ul></li><li>If a face <strong>was found</strong>, the recognition task concludes, and the system transitions to the <strong>inquiry task</strong>.</li></ul></li></ul><p>(The chart is genrated by ChatGPT.)</p></li></ol><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://allenzhuer.github.io/picx-images-hosting/Face_recognition.2kryc1wfy6.svg"                      alt="Visitor identification"                ></p><p>Face Recognition will be introduced in a new blog for the learning path in Face Recognition.  <em><strong>TODO: Face recognition blog link.</strong></em></p><h2 id="Voice-based-greeting-function"><a href="#Voice-based-greeting-function" class="headerlink" title="Voice-based greeting function"></a>Voice-based greeting function</h2><p>The IFLYTEK voice transcription realizes a voice-based greeting function to obtain voice information, which will be stored in the database with face information and personal information. (I have not learned NLP then, so have to turn to open-source tech or tools for help.)</p><p>The inquiry task module leverages a <strong>microphone array</strong>, an <strong>RGB-D camera</strong>, and a <strong>speech output module</strong> to interact with household members and collect their preferences. For example, the robot might ask, <em>“What’s your favorite drink?”</em> Upon receiving a response, it converts the speech to text, detects keywords (e.g., Sprite, Coke, milk tea), and stores the data for future use.</p><p><strong>Process Flow</strong></p><ol><li><strong>Module Initialization</strong>:<ul><li>Start the <strong>RGB-D camera thread</strong> and <strong>microphone array thread</strong>.</li><li>Rotate the camera to search for faces.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Face Detection</strong>:<ul><li>Once a single face is detected, the camera aligns to keep the face centered.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Interactive Questioning</strong>:<ul><li>The robot asks: <em>“What’s your name?”</em> Processes and saves the name.</li><li>Then asks: <em>“What’s your favorite drink?”</em> Transcribes the response and extracts key preferences.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Data Storage</strong>:<ul><li>The system links the detected face with the name and preferences.</li><li>Packages the data into a structured record in the database.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Repeating the Process</strong>:<ul><li>After one member’s information is collected, the system checks for other undetected faces.</li><li>If faces remain, the camera rotates to locate another person and repeats the inquiry process.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Task Completion</strong>:<ul><li>When all faces have been detected and information collected, the module concludes the inquiry task and transitions to the <strong>guidance task</strong>.</li></ul></li></ol><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://allenzhuer.github.io/picx-images-hosting/image.6wqrjom36d.webp"                      alt="Voice-based greeting function"                > </p><p>(The chart is genrated by ChatGPT.)</p><h2 id="Guidance-function"><a href="#Guidance-function" class="headerlink" title="Guidance function"></a>Guidance function</h2><p>The primary functionalities required for this task include <strong>Marker search and recognition</strong>, <strong>motion planning</strong>, and <strong>obstacle avoidance</strong>. Each function works in harmony to ensure the robot can execute tasks efficiently and safely. The markers are used for turtlebot, and it can be replaced by pre-programming in Moro robot system to guide to the pre-defined places. </p><p>You can visit the blog regrading to the Motion planning and Obstacle avoidance to learn the specific algorithms.  <em><strong>TODO: Motion planning blog links.</strong></em></p><h4 id="Process-flow"><a href="#Process-flow" class="headerlink" title="Process flow"></a><strong>Process flow</strong></h4><ol><li>The robot initializes the task by scanning for the first marker to determine its starting point.</li><li>Upon detecting a marker:<ul><li>The marker’s information is decoded to determine the next action.</li><li>The robot plans its route to the specified target area.</li></ul></li><li>During navigation:<ul><li>Obstacles are detected and avoided using real-time LiDAR data.</li><li>The robot updates its path dynamically to ensure smooth movement.</li></ul></li><li>If the robot reaches the final marker, it concludes the task or transitions to a new task as per the marker’s instructions.</li></ol><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://allenzhuer.github.io/picx-images-hosting/image.60ua4ckstu.webp"                      alt="Guidance function"                ></p><h2 id="Grasp-Function"><a href="#Grasp-Function" class="headerlink" title="Grasp Function"></a>Grasp Function</h2><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://allenzhuer.github.io/picx-images-hosting/image.60ua4ckstu.webp"                      alt="image"                ></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Introduction&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an era where artificial int</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Robotics" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Robotics/"/>
    
    <category term="HCI" scheme="http://example.com/tags/HCI/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to Analyze DeFi Projects</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2023/09/12/How-to-Analyze-DeFi-Projects/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2023/09/12/How-to-Analyze-DeFi-Projects/</id>
    <published>2023-09-12T02:45:18.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-10-27T05:02:04.262Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="How-to-Analyze-DeFi-Projects"><a href="#How-to-Analyze-DeFi-Projects" class="headerlink" title="How to Analyze DeFi Projects"></a>How to Analyze DeFi Projects</h1><p><strong>Introduction:</strong></p><ul><li>This article focuses on explaining the thought process and not on commenting on or analyzing any specific project.</li><li>Before diving into a deep analysis, understanding the fundamentals of a DeFi project is extremely important.</li><li>Tracking popular metrics of DeFi protocols can help investors assess the health of the project and evaluate whether it is undervalued or overvalued.</li><li>By understanding token economics, investors can make wiser decisions about which tokens to buy, sell, and hold.</li><li>The technology underpinning DeFi projects is a key factor in determining its feasibility and effectiveness.</li><li>The team’s pursuit of security is of paramount importance.</li><li>Investors need to be able to identify projects that align with the use cases they believe in and evaluate the team behind them.</li><li>The strength of a project’s community and the extent to which it is adopted by users are also important indicators of success.</li></ul><h2 id="Introduction-to-DeFi"><a href="#Introduction-to-DeFi" class="headerlink" title="Introduction to DeFi"></a>Introduction to DeFi</h2><p>The explosive growth of Decentralized Finance (DeFi) has fundamentally transformed the financial field, offering a variety of innovative products and services. As a result, individuals can now access unprecedented financial services and products without having to go through intermediaries like banks or traditional financial institutions.</p><p>DeFi has made finance more accessible, allowing anyone with an internet connection to participate in activities like lending, trading, and earning interest on their digital assets. However, as more and more projects enter the market, understanding how to effectively analyze DeFi projects has become crucial. This means that investors should conduct thorough due diligence on a project before acquiring its tokens.</p><h2 id="Understanding-the-Basics-of-DeFi"><a href="#Understanding-the-Basics-of-DeFi" class="headerlink" title="Understanding the Basics of DeFi"></a>Understanding the Basics of DeFi</h2><p>Before diving into a deep analysis, understanding the fundamentals of a DeFi project is essential. DeFi refers to financial applications built on blockchain networks, aiming to offer open, permissionless, and trustless alternatives to traditional financial services. These projects usually provide services like lending, decentralized exchanges, and liquidity mining.</p><p>Considering the open and permissionless nature of this technology, various individuals and teams are building applications that cover many use cases, such as giving users unprecedented control over their personal data and complete ownership of their digital assets. For those new to the DeFi field, they should approach these projects with caution and prudence.</p><h2 id="Why-is-Due-Diligence-Risk-Management-in-DeFi-Important"><a href="#Why-is-Due-Diligence-Risk-Management-in-DeFi-Important" class="headerlink" title="Why is Due Diligence (Risk Management) in DeFi Important?"></a>Why is Due Diligence (Risk Management) in DeFi Important?</h2><p>Due to the unique nature and risks of the rapidly evolving field of DeFi, conducting due diligence before investing or purchasing tokens is extremely important. DeFi investments often come with risks such as potential scams, hacking attacks, and the loss of part or all of the investor’s principal. By thoroughly evaluating a project’s fundamentals, team, technology, and security measures, one can avoid potential scams or bad projects. By conducting due diligence, investors can make decisions, reduce risks, and identify investment opportunities that align with their investment goals and risk tolerance. Moreover, it will help build the necessary knowledge and understanding foundation to invest in the complex and rapidly growing field of DeFi.</p><p>This requires individuals involved in the DeFi field to consider the following factors when engaging with new projects. </p><h2 id="Fundamentals-of-the-Project"><a href="#Fundamentals-of-the-Project" class="headerlink" title="Fundamentals of the Project"></a>Fundamentals of the Project</h2><p>Understanding the core aspects of a project, such as its purpose, utility, value proposition, and roadmap, is key. Assessing the market size and growth potential of the project is also essential. Reading the whitepaper can provide insights into the project’s objectives, use cases, and technology. The track record of team members reveals their ability to build and scale the product. Finally, the roadmap can be used to judge whether the project is proceeding as planned. It can serve as a supplement to other research, determining the likelihood of the project reaching its milestone goals.</p><h2 id="Popular-metrics-of-DeFi-Protocols"><a href="#Popular-metrics-of-DeFi-Protocols" class="headerlink" title="Popular metrics of DeFi Protocols"></a>Popular metrics of DeFi Protocols</h2><p>There are several popular indicators that can provide valuable references to understand the performance and potential of a DeFi project. These include the token’s Total Value Locked (TVL), 24-hour trading volume, inflation rate, price, and market cap.</p><h3 id="Total-Value-Locked-TVL"><a href="#Total-Value-Locked-TVL" class="headerlink" title="Total Value Locked (TVL)"></a>Total Value Locked (TVL)</h3><p>Total Value Locked (TVL) is the total amount of funds locked in a DeFi protocol. You can view TVL as the total amount deposited by liquidity providers into a protocol. For example, as of July 2023, Uniswap’s TVL exceeds 3.8 billion USD, meaning users have deposited more than $3.8 billion into Uniswap. You can review TVL to assess the overall interest in a specific DeFi protocol or use it to compare which DeFi protocols have “locked” more value. Attracting substantial TVL is often a sign of a strong project.</p><h3 id="Market-Cap"><a href="#Market-Cap" class="headerlink" title="Market Cap"></a>Market Cap</h3><p>The market cap reflects the total value of circulating tokens in a DeFi protocol. It is calculated by multiplying the current price of the token by the number of tokens in circulation. The market cap provides an overall assessment of the protocol’s size and prominence. However, it must be considered in conjunction with other factors such as the utility of the protocol and competition.</p><h3 id="24-hour-Trading-Volume"><a href="#24-hour-Trading-Volume" class="headerlink" title="24-hour Trading Volume"></a>24-hour Trading Volume</h3><p>The 24-hour trading volume measures the total value of transactions executed in a specific DeFi protocol over a 24-hour span. A high 24-hour trading volume indicates that the project is more active and has better liquidity, reflecting an active ecosystem and increased market interest. Conversely, a low 24-hour trading volume shows less buying and selling of the protocol’s tokens, and lower liquidity. Low 24-hour trading volume may signify a lack of interest or participation from traders and investors.</p><h3 id="Inflation-Rate"><a href="#Inflation-Rate" class="headerlink" title="Inflation Rate"></a>Inflation Rate</h3><p>Another important indicator is the inflation rate, referring to the rate at which new tokens are generated within the DeFi protocol. A lower inflation rate might be favorable, as it indicates a more controllable token supply, possibly increasing in value over time, such as ETH transitioning to a deflationary state after moving to POS, and BTC halving, where the new BTC output will be halved. However, assessing the overall token economy and allocation model to ensure a balance between incentivizing participants and maintaining token scarcity is crucial. This topic will be further explored in this article.</p><h3 id="Market-Cap-to-Total-Value-Locked-Ratio-TVL-Ratio"><a href="#Market-Cap-to-Total-Value-Locked-Ratio-TVL-Ratio" class="headerlink" title="Market Cap to Total Value Locked Ratio (TVL Ratio)"></a>Market Cap to Total Value Locked Ratio (TVL Ratio)</h3><p>The Market Cap to TVL ratio provides investors with information about the relationship between a DeFi project’s valuation and demand. For example, if a protocol’s token market cap is low but its TVL is high, it may mean that the token is undervalued. If a token’s TVL ratio is below 1, it may be more attractive, suitable for potential investors.</p><h3 id="Number-of-Addresses"><a href="#Number-of-Addresses" class="headerlink" title="Number of Addresses"></a>Number of Addresses</h3><p>The number of wallet addresses is an indicator that measures the number of DeFi protocol participants. Similar to the user numbers of traditional Web2 applications, it is used to gauge user engagement. An increase in address numbers may be a good sign of growing popularity and adoption. It should be noted that this metric might be manipulated, as in the case of airdrops where an investor might have multiple addresses. Investors should use this metric in conjunction with other indicators.</p><h2 id="Tokenomics"><a href="#Tokenomics" class="headerlink" title="Tokenomics"></a>Tokenomics</h2><p>Tokenomics is a term that originates from the fusion of “token” and “economics.” It is a key concept in the cryptocurrency domain, referring to the economic principles and incentive systems for managing the creation, distribution, and value of tokens within a specific blockchain system.</p><p>Here are some aspects that tokenomics considers:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Token Supply and Issuance</strong>: This involves the total number of existing or to-be-issued tokens. Some tokens have a fixed supply, while others may have a mechanism to mint new tokens. Issuance mechanisms can significantly influence the price and overall economy of the tokens. Fixed supply may lead to scarcity and possibly increase the price but might limit the system’s flexibility. Mintable tokens offer greater flexibility but could lead to inflation if mismanaged. For example, MATIC originally had a fixed supply cap of 10 billion, while the POL white paper allows for a specific rate of annual increase beyond the initial supply of 10 billion (all converted from MATIC).</p></li><li><p><strong>Token Distribution</strong>: How tokens are distributed among users can greatly impact the health and sustainability of the token economy. Fair and reasonable distribution helps maintain a healthy and active user base. Additionally, tokens may be distributed according to a vesting schedule, meaning they can be used within specific periods. This can encourage long-term holding and contribute to the token’s stability.</p></li><li><p><strong>Token Utility</strong>: Tokens usually serve specific functions within their ecosystem. They can provide services, voting rights, or other benefits to users. The utility of a token is a key factor in determining its value. Tokens that provide services, voting rights, or other benefits are more likely to retain value than those without clear use cases.</p></li><li><p><strong>Mining and Staking Incentives</strong>: Many blockchain projects reward users for contributing to network security and stability with newly minted tokens, a practice known as mining or staking. Participation in incentive measures like staking rewards can encourage user engagement. However, this must be balanced to avoid vicious inflation or other unintended consequences.</p></li><li><p><strong>Token Burning</strong>: Some projects may choose to periodically “burn” tokens, permanently removing them from circulation to reduce supply and potentially increase the value of the remaining tokens.</p></li><li><p><strong>Governance</strong>: Many tokens also serve as governance tokens, granting holders voting rights over the project’s future decisions.</p></li><li><p><strong>Economic Policies</strong>: Tokenomics involves implementing economic policies at the protocol level, influencing how tokens are issued, distributed, and managed.</p></li><li><p><strong>Security</strong>: The security of tokens and their underlying blockchain technology is crucial. This includes the security of smart contracts managing the tokens and the overall security of the blockchain.</p></li></ul><p>Tokenomics is vital as it shapes the dynamics of digital assets and projects. By understanding tokenomics, investors can make more informed decisions about buying and holding particular tokens. It can also help project developers design more sustainable and successful token economies. Equally important, remember that the above-mentioned aspects are just things to consider; the “best” token economy may vary depending on the specific goals of the project. For instance, tokens aimed at incentivizing participation in decentralized applications may have different requirements compared to tokens intended to act as stablecoins.</p><h2 id="Assessing-DeFi-Technology"><a href="#Assessing-DeFi-Technology" class="headerlink" title="Assessing DeFi Technology"></a>Assessing DeFi Technology</h2><p>The technology that underpins DeFi (Decentralized Finance) projects is a critical factor in determining their feasibility and effectiveness. One of the key aspects to consider is the blockchain platform on which the project is built. For example, Ethereum is a popular choice, providing a robust and mature infrastructure for DeFi applications. Meanwhile, with the development of Layer 2 solutions, more and more projects are seeking collaboration with OP and ARB. Other Layer 1 blockchain have also emerged, offering promising options for scalable DeFi applications. Investors seeking to acquire DeFi tokens should weigh the pros and cons of the underlying blockchain to make an informed decision.</p><p>Another crucial aspect is the assessment of the smart contracts that drive the DeFi projects. Smart contracts are self-executing contracts on the blockchain, with the terms of the agreement directly written into code. Although audits may not necessarily guarantee security, it is vital for DeFi projects to regularly audit their smart contracts to reduce potential vulnerabilities and protect user funds. Reviewing the smart contract audit history of a project can give insights into the team’s efforts to protect users.</p><p>Interoperability is another key aspect of DeFi tokens, ensuring seamless communication and interaction between different platforms and protocols. It allows tokens to be easily transferred, traded, and used across multiple decentralized applications (DApps) and blockchain networks. Investors should check the interoperability of DeFi tokens before deciding to invest.</p><h2 id="Security"><a href="#Security" class="headerlink" title="Security"></a>Security</h2><p>Given the frequent occurrence of security vulnerabilities in the DeFi (Decentralized Finance) sector, assessing a project’s security measures is crucial. Regular audits by reputable third-party companies, which indicate that the project is actively identifying potential vulnerabilities to ensure the security of smart contracts, are a positive sign. Considering the history of DeFi projects being targeted by hackers and the subsequent panic that ensues, robust security measures are a necessity.</p><p>In addition to audits, incentives similar to bounty hunters exist, such as bug bounty programs, which serve as another indicator of the project’s serious commitment to security. In a bug bounty program, the organization sets specific standards, guidelines, and rewards for individuals who discover and responsibly disclose valid security vulnerabilities. When bug finders identify vulnerabilities, they can submit a detailed report to the organization, outlining the issue, its impact, and the steps to reproduce the flaw. The organization then verifies the reported vulnerability, and if valid, offers a bounty or predetermined monetary reward to the bug-finder. This proactive approach to security encourages a community of security researchers to help improve the overall safety and resilience of the DeFi project.</p><h2 id="Team"><a href="#Team" class="headerlink" title="Team"></a>Team</h2><p>The following are common points to consider in team assessment for stock investments, which may be enlightening for evaluating teams within DeFi (Decentralized Finance) projects:</p><ul><li><strong>Assessing the Skills, Experience, and Qualifications of Team Members:</strong> Look for signs of success in similar enterprises or industries. The collective ability of the team should align with the company’s mission and goals.</li><li><strong>Researching the Team’s Compensation Structure:</strong> This includes salary, bonuses, and stock options (or token allocation in the context of DeFi). Stock options can inflate compensation figures and affect shareholder value. High compensation that doesn’t align with the company’s performance might be a warning signal.</li><li><strong>Observing Insider Buying and Stock (or Token) Repurchases:</strong> If management is purchasing company stock (or tokens), it might indicate their confidence in the company’s future. Conversely, if management is selling stock (or tokens), it may signal potential problems.</li><li><strong>Paying Attention to How Management Communicates with Shareholders and the Public:</strong> Transparency, regular updates, and a clear vision for the company’s future are all signs of strong leadership. Questions can be asked through social media, community channels, and AMAs (Ask Me Anything sessions).</li><li><strong>Company Policies and Mission Statements:</strong> These can provide deep insights into management’s values and strategic direction. Look for evidence of ethical practices and a focus on long-term profitability.</li><li><strong>Being Alert to Potential Red Flags:</strong> Such as past fraudulent activities or ongoing legal issues.</li></ul><p>In the context of DeFi projects, these traditional considerations take on new dimensions, given the decentralized and often pseudonymous nature of blockchain projects. Still, careful analysis of the team’s background, alignment with project goals, compensation structure, and communication strategy can provide valuable insights into the project’s credibility, alignment with stakeholders’ interests, and long-term viability.</p><h2 id="Community-and-Social-Media"><a href="#Community-and-Social-Media" class="headerlink" title="Community and Social Media"></a>Community and Social Media</h2><p>The strength of a project’s community and user adoption is a key indicator of its potential success. These metrics provide valuable insights into the project’s viability, future growth prospects, and overall market acceptance.</p><ul><li>**Emotions and Engagement: ** Emotion is an essential factor in trading and also a reflection of the strength of a project’s community. Engaging with the project’s community is vital to deeply understanding their sentiment, active participation, and overall enthusiasm. This interaction allows you to assess the levels of support, engagement, and trust within the community.</li><li>**Social Media Platforms: ** Platforms like Twitter, Telegram, Discord, and even WeChat provide abundant information about the project community. Investors should monitor discussions, comments, and activity levels on these platforms, looking for signs of positive sentiment, active discussions, and growing follower numbers.</li><li><strong>Positive Sentiment:</strong> Positive sentiment indicates community trust and enthusiasm for the project. It’s often reflected in the tone and content of discussions within social media channels.</li><li><strong>Community Activities:</strong> Participation in community forums, AMAs (Ask Me Anything sessions), and active community channels often indicates a thriving community that is engaged and supportive of the project.</li><li><strong>Warning Signs:</strong> On the flip side, investors should be cautious about manipulated sentiment, paid influencers, or unnatural spikes in activity that could be signs of artificial hype or misleading marketing strategies.</li><li><strong>Importance of Community in DeFi:</strong> In the world of decentralized finance (DeFi), community plays an even more significant role. Decisions related to the development and direction of a project often involve community voting and active participation from the stakeholders. A strong community can foster innovation, support the project through challenges, and contribute to the decentralized ethos that underpins these projects.</li></ul><p>Evaluating the community and social media presence of a DeFi project is a multifaceted task. It requires a nuanced understanding of various platforms, the ability to discern genuine sentiment from manipulation, and an appreciation for the role of the community in driving project success. Combined with other assessment factors like technology, security, and team evaluation, community analysis offers a holistic view of a project’s potential and can guide wise investment decisions.</p><h2 id="VC-investment"><a href="#VC-investment" class="headerlink" title="VC investment"></a>VC investment</h2><p>Venture Capital (VC) investment in a crypto project can have substantial impacts, both positive and negative. Here’s an analysis of how VC investment may affect a crypto or decentralized finance (DeFi) project:</p><h3 id="Positive-Impacts"><a href="#Positive-Impacts" class="headerlink" title="Positive Impacts"></a>Positive Impacts</h3><ul><li><p><strong>Increased Capital</strong>: VC funding provides the necessary capital to scale the project, develop technology, hire talent, and execute the roadmap. It can accelerate growth and enable the project to reach milestones more quickly.</p></li><li><p><strong>Network and Expertise</strong>: VCs often come with vast industry networks and strategic insights. These connections can help in forming partnerships, gaining market insights, and providing mentorship to the team.</p></li><li><p><strong>Trust</strong>: Backing from renowned VCs can bring trust to the project. It signals trust and often attracts further institutional and retail interest.</p></li><li><p><strong>Marketing and Community Building</strong>: VC investment can facilitate more substantial marketing efforts and community engagement, which can result in better visibility and adoption.</p></li></ul><h3 id="Negative-Impacts"><a href="#Negative-Impacts" class="headerlink" title="Negative Impacts"></a>Negative Impacts</h3><ul><li><p><strong>Control and Decision-making</strong>: Depending on the terms, VC investment may come with conditions that affect control and decision-making within the project. VCs might seek seats on the board or have a say in major decisions, potentially leading to conflicts with the original vision of the founders.</p></li><li><p><strong>Token Distribution and Economics</strong>: If not managed carefully, the token distribution to VCs might affect the token economics, potentially leading to an oversupply or concentration of tokens with a few entities. This can impact price stability and community dynamics.</p></li><li><p><strong>Exit Pressure</strong>: VC funds usually seek returns on their investment within a defined period. This can lead to pressures on the project to deliver financial results, sometimes at the expense of long-term innovation or community interests.</p></li><li><p><strong>Potential Misalignment with Decentralization Ethos</strong>: In some cases, VC involvement might be seen as contrary to the decentralized ethos of crypto projects, especially if there’s significant control exerted by the VCs. This could lead to community backlash or a shift away from the project’s original decentralized mission.</p></li></ul><p>VC investment in a crypto project is a multifaceted aspect that carries both opportunities and challenges. While it provides much-needed capital and potential strategic advantages, it also introduces complexities related to control, token economics, and alignment with the project’s vision and values.</p><p>Projects considering VC investment must carefully assess and negotiate the terms to ensure alignment with their long-term goals, community interests, and decentralized principles if they pertain to the specific project. Transparency with the community and stakeholders about the nature and terms of the investment can also be vital in maintaining trust and alignment.</p><h2 id="Conclusion"><a href="#Conclusion" class="headerlink" title="Conclusion"></a>Conclusion</h2><p>Analyzing DeFi projects is a critical process in making informed investment decisions in the rapidly expanding field of decentralized finance. While the factors outlined above are essential for making wise choices, what’s even more vital is that investments should never exceed what one can afford to lose. Investors should proceed with caution, not only fully understanding the technical foundation, security measures, team competence, community engagement, and social media impact of the project but also scrutinizing potential risks and market volatility. VC investment may bring new opportunities and challenges, and this too requires careful assessment. Ultimately, investing in DeFi or any crypto projects should be based on comprehensive research and understanding, coupled with clear investment strategies and risk management plans. While pursuing returns, maintaining caution and responsibility is of paramount importance.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;How-to-Analyze-DeFi-Projects&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#How-to-Analyze-DeFi-Projects&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;How to Analyze DeFi Projects&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ho</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="DeFi" scheme="http://example.com/tags/DeFi/"/>
    
    <category term="Investment" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Investment/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>THE LEAN PRODUCT PROCESS</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2022/09/12/THE-LEAN-PRODUCT-PROCESS/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2022/09/12/THE-LEAN-PRODUCT-PROCESS/</id>
    <published>2022-09-12T01:01:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-12T02:54:50.390Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="THE-LEAN-PRODUCT-PROCESS"><a href="#THE-LEAN-PRODUCT-PROCESS" class="headerlink" title="THE LEAN PRODUCT PROCESS"></a>THE LEAN PRODUCT PROCESS</h1><p><em>The Lean Product Playbook</em> written by Dan Olsen shows a detailed guide on how to find product markets and make products people love. Unlike some books that are long in theory and short in practice, this is the first book I’ve read that really explains how to apply Lean Startup concepts in a practical, step-by-step manner. I’m so glad to have the book when I have the passion to build something inspired. </p><p>And this note is more about listing some topics I really love in this book.</p><h1 id="Core-concepts"><a href="#Core-concepts" class="headerlink" title="Core concepts"></a>Core concepts</h1><p>The journey starts with why products failed and followed by the <em><strong>product-market fit</strong></em>, which captures the essence of what it means to build a great product. </p><blockquote><p>Product-market fit:</p><p>My definition of product-market fit…is that you have to build a product that creates significant customer value. This means that your product meets real customer needs and does so in a way that is better than the alternatives.</p></blockquote><p>I used to pay more attention to some ideas or concepts like advertisement, marketing, business models, and how to increase the customer lifetime value, and this definition tells me there is a distinction between <em>creating</em> and <em>capturing</em> values in the process. In order to capture values, you have to create it first.</p><p>The other core concept in this book is the <em><strong>Problem Space and Solution Space</strong></em>. </p><blockquote><p>Any product that you actually build exists in solution space, as do any product designs that you create—such as mockups, wireframes, or prototypes.</p><p>Problem space is where all the customer needs that you’d like your product to deliver live.</p></blockquote><p>And the customer needs can be expanded to some other concepts like job-to-be-done, customer desires, or customer pain points. I attained many courses who starts with idetifying the job-to-be-done, which emphasizes the importace of finding what not be done or well to solve customers real problems. And sometimes I find that some blogs or books often talk about the differences between the “what” versus the “how.” The “what” describes the benefits that the product should give the customer—what the product will accomplish for the user. The “how” is the way in which the product delivers the “what” to the customer. The “how” is the design of the product and the specific technology used to implement the product. “What” is problem space and “how” is solution space.</p><h1 id="The-Lean-product-process"><a href="#The-Lean-product-process" class="headerlink" title="The Lean product process"></a>The Lean product process</h1><p>The content of product management process can be divided into these steps:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Determine your target customers.</strong> This is the bottom of our pyramid since different customers will have different needs and even those who have the same needs may have different views on their relative importance. </p></li><li><p><strong>Identify underserved customer needs.</strong> Before we mover to design a solution, we have to validate the job-to-be-done, customer pain points or customer desires. Since customer needs can seem somewhat fuzzy when we interview them, and they are not skilled at describe the roots of the problem.</p></li><li><p><strong>Define your value proposition.</strong> At this point, we have identified several important customer needs, now we need to decide which ones our product or service will address. </p></li><li><p><strong>Specify your MVP feature set.</strong> Now we have a clear understanding of our value proposition, we have decided on the feature set for our MVP, identifying functionality required to validating we are heading on the right direction.</p></li><li><p><strong>Create your MVP prototype.</strong> At this stage, we want to create a user experience or prototype that we can show to customers so that we can test our ideas.</p></li><li><p><strong>Test your MVP with customers.</strong> In this part, we conduct both qualitative and quotative user test to see how it compares to the target value. </p></li><li><p><strong>Then Iterate to improve product-market fit.</strong> I learned a loop called ‘build-measure-learn’, which means we want to use what we have learned after we receive a round of feedbacks to modify our hypotheses and MVP so that we can test them with customers again. We want to iterate quickly with the goal of improving product-market fit.</p></li></ul><p>Some tasks will be performed in these steps:</p><ul><li><p>Understanding and representing user needs.</p></li><li><p>Defining a vision for a product.</p></li><li><p>Monitoring the market and developing competitive analyses.</p></li><li><p>Aligning stakeholders around the vision for the product.</p></li><li><p>Prioritizing product features and capabilities.</p></li><li><p>Creating a shared brain across larger teams to empower independent decision-making.</p></li></ul><p>There are some benefits of Lean or agile management. First, because we are planning in smaller increments, we can react to changes in the market or new information more quickly. Second, our product can reach customers earlier, which means that we can start hearing feedbacks from customers on our actual products sooner, which helps guide our subsequent product management efforts. Third, teams can reduce their margin of error in estimating scope by working in smaller batch sizes.</p><p><em>TBC… Some concepts in Agile will be added, and some tools will be here in the future after I have the experience of the whole loop. Some other ideas can be the link and differences between design thinking and the lean product process. From a lifelong learning perspective, how to be a good problem-solver?</em></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;THE-LEAN-PRODUCT-PROCESS&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#THE-LEAN-PRODUCT-PROCESS&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;THE LEAN PRODUCT PROCESS&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;THE LEAN PRODU</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to solve problems?</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2022/09/12/How-to-solve-problems/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2022/09/12/How-to-solve-problems/</id>
    <published>2022-09-12T00:35:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-12T00:43:13.939Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="How-to-solve-problems-TBC"><a href="#How-to-solve-problems-TBC" class="headerlink" title="How to solve problems? (TBC)"></a>How to solve problems? (TBC)</h1><p>Nowadays, people are hired not only to realize functions, but more to solve problems. Besides that, in personal life, we are around by various problems. One day, if we are given a problem, how to solve it effectively? And how to be a good problem solver?</p><h1 id="1-Types-of-Problems"><a href="#1-Types-of-Problems" class="headerlink" title="1.  Types of Problems"></a>1.  Types of Problems</h1><p>Before rushing into how to solve problems, let’s start with the types of problems.</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://cdn.staticaly.com/gh/AllenZhuer/image-hosting@master/images/Xnip2022-09-12_08-39-34.5kiie8k66og0.webp"                      alt="Types of problems"                ></p><p>This idea is coming form Problem-Solving: The Owner’s Manual by Pierce Howard, which can be combined with Bohn’s talking about the link between causes and effects in class. Figure 1 shows the types of problems with the general activities to solve them in blue rectangles. Problems can be divided into two parts: solutions are known and unknown. In the first part where solutions are known, the ideal type is the best solution to a problem is obvious based on complete knowledge, then we implement it. If the best solution is not obvious, where we have solutions with certain outcomes, then we should compare and decide one best solution. Sometimes, we have solutions with uncertain outcomes. What we must react is to decide which solution has the highest probability of success. One example here can be how to choose the best design of the garden for maximum residents’ satisfaction. If the potential solutions are in a jumbled list without priority, what we do can be determining the priority order based on the effects. But complete knowledge situation rarely happens. Most times problems come in a way we are not familiar with. If the cause is unknown, the first thing we should do is finding the cause. If the cause is known or irrelevant, we can generate ideas that could fix the problem. So, the messages to take can be different based on the types of problems, which depends on our state of knowledge. </p><h1 id="2-The-process-to-solve-problems"><a href="#2-The-process-to-solve-problems" class="headerlink" title="2.  The process to solve problems"></a>2.  The process to solve problems</h1><p>Problem solving is a process, consisting of 4 key stages, which can be divided to problem definition, solutions generation, evaluating and choosing best solution, and solution validation.</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://cdn.staticaly.com/gh/AllenZhuer/image-hosting@master/images/Xnip2022-09-12_08-39-50.3vx50pkfh960.webp"                      alt="stages to solve problems"                ></p><p>Figure 2: 4 stages to solve problems</p><p>To solve problem effectively and creatively, the first stage should be defining the problem we want to solve. Identify the stakeholders who have a say in the way we solve this problem and what they want. Then describe the vision which should include is the trouble trying to solve now. By asking whys to get the potential root causes we need to address. Then try to write down what we want to achieve in the future. Sometimes we can even get the key factors based on prior knowledge and experience. Some tools may help a lot here, like fishbone diagram to the causes. Some people tend to answer the first problem without checking if this is the right we really want to solve.</p><p>In the next stage, generating solutions. After discovering the real problem that we really want to solve, try to concentrate on generating many solutions such as a target 20 potential alternatives and should not evaluate them at all. Many times, an idea that would have been thrown away immediately, if evaluating properly, can develop into an excellent solution.</p><p>The third stage should be evaluating and choosing the best solution. In evaluating step, some constraints should be taken into consideration like cost, safety, policy, etc. Write the good points and bad points of every solution and state the unique point after looking through all the constraints and targets for all potential solutions. Sometimes, numbers and facts will help us decide the final solutions if the solution can show certain outcomes. For solutions with uncertain outcomes, decision to the best one may be made by feeling, which can be the result of our skills, experience, and knowledgement, place in the right limiting circumstance. Some tools like SWOT can help us to shortlist our potential choices. Besides that, we can also ask our team members for voting. If all the solutions cannot meet the needs, we may go back to the start of the cycle to check the problem statement and go the journey again.</p><p>The last stage should be validating the final solution. The beginning of this stage is deciding how we will make the solution happen. Testing will be made serval times and confirming that the solution has been carried out as planned. Ask our stakeholders’ feedbacks and evaluate the results. Then make the next plan to improve and integrate.</p><h1 id="3-How-to-be-a-creative-problem-solver"><a href="#3-How-to-be-a-creative-problem-solver" class="headerlink" title="3.  How to be a creative problem solver?"></a>3.  How to be a creative problem solver?</h1><p>After learning how to apply different models and tools to solve problems, maybe we can solve new problems we are not familiar, but can we always get a creative and effective solution? The answer is no. But we can always get useful solutions by developing our personality traits. </p><p>After the journey to understand what creativity is, I was totally attracted by these brilliant artists and innovators, leading me on a trip to discover what makes us creative, where ideas come from, and how they come to life.</p><p>Creativity is the ability to see a world in a grain of sand and a heaven in a wild flower, hold infinity in the palm of your hand and eternity in an hour. (William Blake) The ability to perceive and produce novel ideas or products that are useful to society. Creativity is the art of problem solving.</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://cdn.staticaly.com/gh/AllenZhuer/image-hosting@master/images/Xnip2022-09-12_08-40-07.196g0gdg8vxc.webp"                      alt="Creativity process and Problem solving"                ></p><p>Figure 3 shows the 4 stages of creativity and problem solving.</p><p>The process starts with preparation, which is all about gathering information. In this stage, we gather related information and materials by conducting users research and empathize with them in order to get the real pain points and define the problem. At this stage, we can use a variety of ideation methods to understand and build problems and ideas from various angles.</p><p>Stage 2 is incubation, where let mind wander. After collecting information in stage 1, take a step away from the ideas before working on them. Open your mind to all ideas unconsciously, and new connections come slowly.</p><p>Next comes the illumination, where shows Eureka. After a period of incubation, insights arise from the deeper layers of the mind, and the ideas show up suddenly. It’s the sudden Eureka moment! </p><p>The fourth stage is about verification and production. Following the Eureka moment, ideas enter your mind and it’s time to evaluate, test, develop, and verify them. At this stage, you will prototype and test your idea to see if it meets the user needs defined in the preparation stage, get feedbacks and learning, then polish it up.</p><p>From these 4 stages, the creativity process oscillates between convergent and divergent thinking. Incubation and illumination are about inspiration, whereas preparation and validation are about generation. To go forward, we should seek the balance between dreaming and doing. Personal traits will show how we will perform the choice. For example, doers will shine in the preparation and verification stages, and dreamers will be the stars in incubation and illumination stages. If you are a doer, sometimes you may find you can really get things done in a brilliant way but lack the new ideas since focusing on the productivity. For a long-term growth, you can read, travel, meet different people, and open your mind to different views. Clean out the space for dream and imagination. For dreamers, who may be stuck too much in their marvelous ideas, try to practice more and apply the skills into real world. </p><p>Quote to end, ‘Know thyself’. We are on a lifelong journey to learn and grow.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;How-to-solve-problems-TBC&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#How-to-solve-problems-TBC&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;How to solve problems? (TBC)&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;How to s</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Notes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why I love Coursera</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2022/08/03/Why-I-love-Coursera/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2022/08/03/Why-I-love-Coursera/</id>
    <published>2022-08-03T05:58:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-08-04T07:11:52.481Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="What-is-my-favourite-application"><a href="#What-is-my-favourite-application" class="headerlink" title="What is my favourite application?"></a>What is my favourite application?</h1><p>Today, I realized I spent more than 10 hours on Coursera every week for the past year and I really enjoyed this platform. Coursera is a platform that you can build skills with online courses from top institutions and universities. I like it since I can learn a lot from top universities whenever and wherever I am, no time, places limits at a low cost or even free. I learnt a lot  courses on it and I really want to introduce it to you. </p><h1 id="How-did-I-know-Coursera"><a href="#How-did-I-know-Coursera" class="headerlink" title="How did I know Coursera?"></a>How did I know Coursera?</h1><p>I still remember the first time I met Coursera when I was learning Deep Learning taught by Andrew Ng, who was a famous professor in Stanford University. At the end of his class in deeplearning.ai, he would introduce us Coursera created by Daphne Koller and himself. MOOC (Massive Open Online Courses) was bringing educational and vocational courses online and Coursera totally won my fragemental time on PC. Similarly, Weixin Reading introduced online reading to the public in China, and became the most visited app on my phone when I was free. </p><h2 id="What-is-the-customer-journey-map"><a href="#What-is-the-customer-journey-map" class="headerlink" title="What is the customer journey map?"></a>What is the customer journey map?</h2><p>The general process of an individual user can be divided into the following steps.</p><ul><li>Log in as individual user or enterprise users</li><li>Find the courses you want by searching jobs, skills, or universities</li><li>Read the introduction of the course and enroll</li><li>Take the course with your customize schedule</li><li>Take all discussions, tests, peer value, and quiz</li><li>Earn a certificate provided by Coursera and institutions</li><li>Share your learning and certificates to LinkedIn or other platforms</li></ul><h1 id="Business-model-of-Coursera"><a href="#Business-model-of-Coursera" class="headerlink" title="Business model of Coursera"></a>Business model of Coursera</h1><h2 id="Who-are-the-customers-Customer-Segments"><a href="#Who-are-the-customers-Customer-Segments" class="headerlink" title="Who are the customers? (Customer Segments)"></a>Who are the customers? (Customer Segments)</h2><p>Coursera provides services to two main kinds customer segments. The first one is educational institutions like universitties and companies, which wants to share course resources with a fully access. The other one can be the end-users who want to learn some skills in specific fields but may find it difficult to get access to educational resources. </p><p>The following types of people can be their potential end-users:</p><ul><li>High school students who want to take college courses in advance.</li><li>College students who want to take online courses rather than offline courses.</li><li>College students who want to learn extracurricular skills.</li><li>Fresh graduate students who want to decide or change career path.</li><li>People who already have a job want to strengthen their existing knowledge.</li><li>People who already have jobs and want to learn new skills.</li></ul><p>Try to imagine this scenario: more and more people realize the importance of life-long learning. As a fresh graduate, Allen is pursuing  a full-time job related to product management, business development. For a better fit, he chooses courses related to digital product managemt, Data analysis, and project managemtn on Coursera and spends 10 hours per week on it. </p><h2 id="What-value-does-Coursera-deliver-to-customers-Value-Propositions"><a href="#What-value-does-Coursera-deliver-to-customers-Value-Propositions" class="headerlink" title="What value does Coursera deliver to customers? (Value Propositions)"></a>What value does Coursera deliver to customers? (Value Propositions)</h2><p>When it comes to what customer needs Coursera want to satisfy, it allows end-users like me easy and complete access to top educational online resources that  many constomers may find unaffordable or inaccessable through its website and application.</p><p>Sharing high-level courses also means that universities and insititutions can reach a greater number of consumers more easily, futhering their individual brand identities. </p><h2 id="How-does-Coursera-make-money-Revenue-Streams"><a href="#How-does-Coursera-make-money-Revenue-Streams" class="headerlink" title="How does Coursera make money? (Revenue Streams)"></a>How does Coursera make money? (Revenue Streams)</h2><p>Courserea starts its journey with the goal of providing high-level education resources for free to anyone looking for it. Now, Coursera charges from several channels to improve its services. </p><h3 id="Free-access"><a href="#Free-access" class="headerlink" title="Free access"></a>Free access</h3><p>There are many ways to get access to some courses for free since some courses are provided to everyone for free. Besides that,  people can choose audition when choose whether to pay for the course so that  they still have access to most course materials for this course without a certificate.</p><h3 id="Certificates"><a href="#Certificates" class="headerlink" title="Certificates"></a>Certificates</h3><p>Most courses are offered with no charge. However, people who want to earn a certificate of completion which is a trusted and shareable way to showcase their new skills can choose to pay the course fee. This feature was landed in 2013, giving paying students access to graded assignments, homework, and examinations. If completed satisfactorily, they can earn a verified certificate at the end of the course, and they can visit the course in the future with no limits. The course fee varies between from <strong>$39</strong> to <strong>$89</strong> depending on the course. Nowadays, people can choose to be a membership with no limits to a sea of courses at a cost of <strong>$39</strong> per month. </p><p>If you have planty time during some period so that you can finish the course within the7-days trail, once finished, you can also get the certificate and have no limits when revisit the course in the future.</p><h3 id="Specializations"><a href="#Specializations" class="headerlink" title="Specializations"></a>Specializations</h3><p>This feature is a bundle of different but related courses designed to help customers  deepen their expertise in a specific area. For example, DeFi: The future Finance Specialization consisted of 4 courses aims to provide learners a much deeper understanding of both the infrastructure of DeFi and leading applications. Customers can pay monthly subscription fees between <strong>$39</strong> to <strong>$89</strong>, depending on the specialization, for access to all resources and specialization certificates.</p><h3 id="Coursera-for-Business"><a href="#Coursera-for-Business" class="headerlink" title="Coursera for Business"></a>Coursera for Business</h3><p>Coursera for Business enables businesses to offer their employees or teams access to a sea of courses to boost their expertise. Compared to traditional certificates, Coursera provides this service with a lower fee of <strong>$400</strong> per employee per year. Enterprise packages comes with higher cost than personal or teams’ plan. Coursera for Campus provides silimar option to the government and universities.</p><p>Since higher price and growing customers in this segment, it has quickly become a key channel of revenue.</p><h3 id="University-Degrees"><a href="#University-Degrees" class="headerlink" title="University Degrees"></a>University Degrees</h3><p>Collaborated with top universities world wide, Coursera offers students a chance to complete a fully recognized Bachelor’s or Master’s Degree, including MBA from UIUC. The price is far lower compared to degrees in campus, but with the same instructors who teach in person. Scholarships are provided. It’s reported that Coursera generated <a href="(https://s27.q4cdn.com/928340662/files/doc_financials/2021/q1/COUR_Earnings-Infographic_Q1-FY21.pdf)">$12.0M</a> in revenue in Q1, 2021 with 13,493 students enrolled. </p><h1 id="Competitve-analysis"><a href="#Competitve-analysis" class="headerlink" title="Competitve analysis"></a>Competitve analysis</h1><h2 id="SWOT-Analysis"><a href="#SWOT-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="SWOT Analysis"></a>SWOT Analysis</h2><h3 id="Strength"><a href="#Strength" class="headerlink" title="Strength"></a>Strength</h3><ul><li>Strong relationships with its key partners to offer colourful and high-level courses.</li><li>First-move advantages: kind of becoming market standard. After Coursera, many universities or educational angency like MOOC China, and MIT opensource, built their own platform which follows these standards. What’s more, the earlier Coursera ran into the market, the bigger market share it would take. Some MOOC platforms like Xue Tang Zai Xian created by Chinese government and universities has limited market usually in domestic rather than a golbal market. </li><li>Good environment to spread courses. Multi-lanuage courses are provided to learners from all over the world. At the same time, Coursera advocates learners to take part in translation event so that subttitle will be translate into their mother language and would be offered after reviews.</li><li>Diverse revenue channels. Multiple revenue model enables Couresera great resources to not only keep competitve to the threat of newcomers but also invest into R&amp;D.</li></ul><h3 id="Weakness"><a href="#Weakness" class="headerlink" title="Weakness"></a>Weakness</h3><ul><li>Services Coursera provided are more focus on solution space, which means more about what can they do. Sometimes they ignore the interests of external stakeholders.</li><li>Poor visual design. Terrible design on both Andriod and iPhone.</li></ul><h3 id="Opportunities"><a href="#Opportunities" class="headerlink" title="Opportunities"></a>Opportunities</h3><ul><li>Covid-19 has changed many people’s lifestyle. Some universities promoted hybrid teaching model, and sea of students were trying to get access to online learning. Even after Covid, people really enjoy online learning since they can follow their own schedule.</li><li>Globalization enables Coursera more international markets. Growth in international market can also help Coursera diversify the risk as it will be less dependent on domestic market for revenue.</li><li>Technology empowering more possibilities. With the development and application of Machine Learning and AI, more smart features including recommendation can be offered to keep customers active.</li></ul><h3 id="Threats"><a href="#Threats" class="headerlink" title="Threats"></a>Threats</h3><ul><li>Government Regulations. Coursera should keep a close eye on the fast changing government regulations under the growing conflicts environment .</li><li>Customers are moving toward mobile  which can hamper the growth as Coursera  still hasn’t got a comprehensive mobile strategy.</li></ul><h1 id="What-can-be-improved"><a href="#What-can-be-improved" class="headerlink" title="What can be improved?"></a>What can be improved?</h1><h2 id="Nice-improvements-from-my-experiences"><a href="#Nice-improvements-from-my-experiences" class="headerlink" title="Nice improvements from my experiences"></a>Nice improvements from my experiences</h2><p>As a customer, although Coursera provides great services,  for more effience and easy of use, some nice improvments can be the following:</p><ul><li><p><strong>A calendar that shows due dates for assignments and quizzes across all of your courses</strong>. When I signed up for 3-4 classes, it’s hard to keep track of what is due and when. Optional email reminders would be a nice touch.</p></li><li><p><strong>Quick feedbacks and colorful interations to keep users active.</strong> Solving small but not so primitive tasks by students could help feeling the progress. And the more types of such quizzes are presented (not just a multiple choice), the more learners will be willing to join. What’s more, peer value and discussion can be offered for students to communicate more to help each other so that they will spend more time on it to get a better understanding and build the willing to learn other related courses.</p></li><li><p><strong>Better interaction design on Mobile application.</strong> A terrible journey starts when open Coursea on both Android and iPhone. It’s difficult for me to get what I want.</p></li><li><p><strong>Better recommendation performance.</strong> Sometimes, after finishing one course, if learners want a deep understanding of specific field, a good recommendation at the end of learning will keep them engaged.</p></li></ul><p>More testing should be conducted so that we can learn from the feedbacks from users and provide higher-perforance services.</p><h2 id="Future-plan"><a href="#Future-plan" class="headerlink" title="Future plan"></a>Future plan</h2><p>Some plans can be taken into consideration for further marketing.</p><ul><li>Conduct geographic analysis to move to new markets.</li><li>Conduct IP analysis to keep competition out of the door.</li><li> Invest more in building an easy-use mobile application.</li><li>Keep existing customers active so that improve their customers life value. Some nice try can be introducing a new product or service of Coursera to existing customers, improving interaction and visual design.</li><li>Improve customer loyalty of Coursera Coursera’s customers. Marketing efforts can be used to increase loyalty among existing customers by organizing events, and by providing post purchase information and services.</li><li>Increase brand awareness. Features like stronger and multiple sharing channels can reach new audiences on social media. What’s more, newcomers have a better chance of choosing a course through a friend’s recommendation.</li></ul><p>More info and market analysis should be conducted to build a good strategy. Will be added soon.</p><h1 id="Thank-you-for-your-time"><a href="#Thank-you-for-your-time" class="headerlink" title="Thank you for your time : )"></a>Thank you for your time : )</h1>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;What-is-my-favourite-application&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#What-is-my-favourite-application&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;What is my favourite applica</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
    <category term="Business Model" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Business-Model/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>如何在Mac上使用Hexo开启博客之旅</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2022/01/12/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%9C%A8Mac%E4%B8%8A%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8Hexo%E5%BC%80%E5%90%AF%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2%E4%B9%8B%E6%97%85/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2022/01/12/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%9C%A8Mac%E4%B8%8A%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8Hexo%E5%BC%80%E5%90%AF%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2%E4%B9%8B%E6%97%85/</id>
    <published>2022-01-12T01:43:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T08:09:13.422Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>之前使用了搭建在阿里云的轻量级服务器中的WordPress开启了我的第一个博客，可是由于使用起来体验不好，困扰我的可能有以下几点：</p><ol><li>使用阿里云轻量级服务器的过程中，一直出现服务器或数据库连接错误的情况。</li><li>在国内的域名需要备案，出国后就希望能够开启一个比较宽松自由的风格。</li><li>我的需求很简单，只是需要有个简洁的地方写点小东西罢了，倘或碰巧被你看见了，那便是我的幸运吧。虽然WordPress可以提供非常丰富的功能，但是嘞，对我来说有些 ‘乱花渐欲迷人眼’。</li></ol><p>于是转到了使用Hexo + Github Pages的静态博客组合，简单明了。</p><h1 id="什么是Hexo呢？"><a href="#什么是Hexo呢？" class="headerlink" title="什么是Hexo呢？"></a>什么是Hexo呢？</h1><p><a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/zh-cn/" >Hexo<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> 是一个快速、简洁且高效的博客框架。嗯，有道理，我喜欢。感兴趣的可以在官网上自行查看更多介绍。</p><h1 id="如何配置环境"><a href="#如何配置环境" class="headerlink" title="如何配置环境"></a>如何配置环境</h1><p>安装 Hexo 相当简单，只需要先安装下列应用程序即可：</p><ul><li><p><a class="link"   href="http://nodejs.org/" >Node.js<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> </p><p>使用使用 <a class="link"   href="https://brew.sh/" >Homebrew<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>安装</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ brew install node</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></li><li><p><a class="link"   href="http://git-scm.com/" >Git<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p>使用 <a class="link"   href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/" >Homebrew<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>, <a class="link"   href="http://www.macports.org/" >MacPorts<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> 或者下载 <a class="link"   href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/git-osx-installer/" >安装程序<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>。</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ brew install git</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></li></ul><ul><li><p>安装Hexo</p><p>所有必备的应用程序安装完成后，即可使用 npm 安装 Hexo。</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ npm install -g hexo-cli</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></li></ul><h1 id="如何搭建博客"><a href="#如何搭建博客" class="headerlink" title="如何搭建博客"></a>如何搭建博客</h1><ol><li><p>在你喜欢的地方建立一个名字为 ‘blog’ 的文件夹（名字也可按你喜欢的来）</p></li><li><p>进入blog文件夹：<code>cd blog</code></p></li><li><p>初始化：<code>hexo init</code></p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/hexo.1u14tv7unpxc.webp"                      alt="hexo" style="zoom:80%;"                 ></li><li><p>启动Hexo：<code>hexo s</code></p><p>之后会出现一个默认的博文，浏览器输入：<a class="link"   href="http://localhost:4000/" >http://localhost:4000<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>，便可查看。</p></li><li><p>新建一篇博文：<code>hexo n &#39;如何在Mac上使用Hexo开启博客之旅&#39;</code></p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/hexo-n.1qlk84t6ch5s.webp"                      alt="hexo-n"                ></p></li></ol><p>​    接下来就在自己喜欢的编辑器里编写吧，我自己使用过Vscode、Typora、以及Obsidian等来写Markdown以及管理自己的笔记。个人推荐Typora：界面简洁，所见即所得。Typora最近开始收费喽，大家看看自己的荷包吧，Obsidian目前仍然免费，但是功能强大，适合建立自己的知识网络，用来写博客是在大材小用。</p><ol start="6"><li><p>在写完后，同样进入到blog文件夹下，运行</p><p>清理：<code>hexo clean</code></p><p>启动：<code>hexo g</code></p><p>生成：<code>hexo s</code></p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/hexo-s.3j4892swnoe0.webp"                      alt="hexo-s"                ></p><p>再次进入<a class="link"   href="http://localhost:4000/" >http://localhost:4000<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>，便可查看你写好的博客了</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/blog.70psm0hpv200.webp"                      alt="blog"                ></p></li></ol><p>到这里搭建博客就已经成功了，接下来是将博客部署到Github上</p><h1 id="Hexo-Github"><a href="#Hexo-Github" class="headerlink" title="Hexo + Github"></a>Hexo + Github</h1><ol><li>**登录github：<a class="link"   href="https://github.com/" >https://github.com<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>，没账号的新建一个，新创建一个仓库New repository，仓库名必须为：<code>昵称.github.io</code>:**，输入描述，创建：</li></ol><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/github.5adlppym0i00.webp"                      alt="github" style="zoom:50%;"                 ><p>​                在这里因为我已经创建过了，所以会显示已经存在账户。</p><ol start="2"><li><p>接着回答terminal中，crtl + c 结束之前的运行，依旧在blog文件夹下部署github的插件：<code>npm install hexo-deployer-git --save</code></p></li><li><p>接着更改blog文件夹下面**_config.yml**的配置，如下</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/blog2.65i7zq6f44c0.webp"                      alt="blog2"                ></p></li></ol><p>​        可以从这里复制：</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">deploy:</span><br><span class="line">  type: git</span><br><span class="line">  repo: https://github.com/AllenZhuer/AllenZhuer.github.io.git</span><br><span class="line">  branch: master</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><ol start="4"><li>最后回到terminal，使用 <code>hexo d</code> 将博客部署到远端。中间会让输入github密码，输入即可，后续部署完成，即可访问你的远端地址。例子就是这样的: <a class="link"   href="https://allenzhuer.github.io/" >https://allenzhuer.github.io/<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></li></ol><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/Xnip2022-01-12_15-51-30.7aop23brb5k0.webp"                      alt="Xnip2022-01-12_15-51-30"                ></p><p>这里呢，由于我使用了主题可能会和你的页面有一些差异，不过也没有问题，接下来我们将开始部署主题。</p><h1 id="选个喜欢的主题吧"><a href="#选个喜欢的主题吧" class="headerlink" title="选个喜欢的主题吧"></a>选个喜欢的主题吧</h1><ol><li>最重要的就是选主题了：<a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/themes/%EF%BC%8C" >https://hexo.io/themes/，<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> 超多主题随你选择。</li></ol><p>我选择的主题为 <a class="link"   href="https://keep-docs.xpoet.cn/" >keep<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>，里面有非常详细的介绍，请移步吧。</p><ol start="2"><li>铛铛，部署完主题后，别忘了它们：</li></ol><p>清理：<code>hexo clean</code></p><p>启动：<code>hexo g</code></p><p>生成：<code>hexo s</code></p><p>部署：<code>hexo d</code></p><p>部署之后，可能有一点点延迟，等一小会儿就行了，捏一捏桌子上的小黄鸭吧。</p><p>如果在你的博客中发现图片加载较慢的问题，推荐一个图床平台 <a class="link"   href="https://picx.xpoet.cn/#/upload" >Picx<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> , 希望能够帮到你。</p><h1 id="域名"><a href="#域名" class="headerlink" title="域名"></a>域名</h1><p>最后一步是购买一个自己喜欢的域名，因为我思来想去的域名已经被别人购买了，并且也没有抱有此博客被许多人看到的想法，所以域名购买暂时告一段落。等到哪天域名过期或者是想到新的域名再来继续更新吧。</p><p>一些购买域名的网站推荐：<a class="link"   href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/jg117mu2-u1HQNLIIIIHJLKORNNO" >NameCheap<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> , <a class="link"   href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/r975xdmjdl09641111021627938" >Godaddy<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> , <a class="link"   href="https://www.namesilo.com/?rid=791ee74iy" >Namesilo<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> 等等。</p><p>如果这篇博客恰巧被你看到并且对你有帮助的话，我将十分开心。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;之前使用了搭建在阿里云的轻量级服务器中的WordPress开启了我的第一个博客，可是由于使用起来体验不好，困扰我的可能有以下几点：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;使用阿里云轻量级服务器的过程中，一直出现服务器或数据库连接错误的情况。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在国内的域名需要备案，出国</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="blog" scheme="http://example.com/tags/blog/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What is a Product Roadmap?</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2022/01/12/What-is-a-Product-Roadmap/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2022/01/12/What-is-a-Product-Roadmap/</id>
    <published>2022-01-12T01:04:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T01:35:18.787Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="What-is-Product-Roadmap"><a href="#What-is-Product-Roadmap" class="headerlink" title="What is Product Roadmap?"></a>What is Product Roadmap?</h1><p>Product Roadmap is a long-term product development plan that gives all product stakeholders the infomation they need to coordinate plans.</p><h2 id="Why-we-need-a-Product-Roadmap"><a href="#Why-we-need-a-Product-Roadmap" class="headerlink" title="Why we need a Product Roadmap?"></a>Why we need a Product Roadmap?</h2><p>A product roadmap provides a prediction to the product development process.</p><h2 id="Who-are-your-product-stakeholders"><a href="#Who-are-your-product-stakeholders" class="headerlink" title="Who are your product stakeholders?"></a>Who are your product stakeholders?</h2><ul><li>Customers</li><li>Customers-facing groups like sales, marketing, and customer support</li><li>Investors, and sponsors</li><li>Architects, designers, and engineers.</li><li>Human resources</li><li>Legal team</li><li>……</li></ul><h2 id="We-need-both-Product-backlog-and-Product-roadmap"><a href="#We-need-both-Product-backlog-and-Product-roadmap" class="headerlink" title="We need both Product backlog and Product roadmap."></a>We need both Product backlog and Product roadmap.</h2><ul><li>You estimate the dates of the product milestones on the roadmap using a completely independent set of top-down estimates from your product development leader. In the end, these estimates are inaccurate, of course. But as long as they’re close, they’ll serve the purposes of the product roadmap, to allow coordination among the different product stakeholders. Increasingly, your backlog will be directed by the product roadmap,which is one of the main ways you ensure that the activities of the product development team are aligned with the needs and goals of the whole company.<h1 id="Laying-the-grooundwork"><a href="#Laying-the-grooundwork" class="headerlink" title="Laying the grooundwork"></a>Laying the grooundwork</h1><h2 id="Why-the-process-is-important"><a href="#Why-the-process-is-important" class="headerlink" title="Why the process is important?"></a>Why the process is important?</h2></li><li> <em><strong>A roadmap has no value if the stakeholders are not aligned in advance.</strong></em></li><li> <em><strong>The fail usually comes from engineers, designers, and the whole team not being exposed to the project early.</strong></em><h2 id="What-are-the-product-development-purposes"><a href="#What-are-the-product-development-purposes" class="headerlink" title="What are the product development purposes?"></a>What are the product development purposes?</h2></li><li>Serve the business.</li><li>Support overall business strategy.</li><li>Win customer adoption, loyalty.</li><li>Generate revenue.<h2 id="How-to-create-alignment"><a href="#How-to-create-alignment" class="headerlink" title="How to create alignment?"></a>How to create alignment?</h2></li><li>Include stakeholders early.</li><li>Ask for, address, feedback.</li><li>Send updates.<h2 id="What-a-successful-Roadmap-need"><a href="#What-a-successful-Roadmap-need" class="headerlink" title="What a successful Roadmap need?"></a>What a successful Roadmap need?</h2></li><li>Sound strategy.</li><li>Realistic.</li><li>Fully supported.<h2 id="How-to-avoid-failures"><a href="#How-to-avoid-failures" class="headerlink" title="How to avoid failures?"></a>How to avoid failures?</h2></li><li>Spend time with stakeholders at the beginning of the process.</li><li>Ask for underlying thoughts.</li><li>Explain the importance of including others.</li><li>Estimate the development time.<h2 id="Select-your-stakeholders"><a href="#Select-your-stakeholders" class="headerlink" title="Select your stakeholders"></a>Select your stakeholders</h2></li><li>Business leader: allocate the resources and prioritize the tasks are necessary to the product sucess.</li><li>Sales leader: They have the target to hit. And they have the ability to rally resources to make the roadmap sucessful.</li><li>Product development leader: They are response for organizing and motivting their team to hit the roadmap milestones.</li><li>When working across groups, use the sales leader as the your business leader.</li></ul><h2 id="Customers-research"><a href="#Customers-research" class="headerlink" title="Customers research"></a>Customers research</h2><p>There are some question have to figure out:</p><ul><li>What decisions do your customer need to make in choosing your product?</li><li>What problem are they trying to solve?</li><li>What other options are available to them?</li></ul><p>And luckily,  there are some ways you can get to your customers:</p><ul><li>Initiate a research group.</li><li>Ask your customer yourself like make an appointment, a phone call, a zoom meeting, etc. Reach out to your customers directly may be the best way to get insights.</li><li>Participate in sales or customer service meetings.</li></ul><h2 id="Start-with-product-strategy"><a href="#Start-with-product-strategy" class="headerlink" title="Start with product strategy"></a>Start with product strategy</h2><p>A product strategy describes how your company will achieve its business goals. And a product strategy should answer the following questions:</p><ul><li>What are your goals?</li><li>How will you measure your sucess?</li><li>Who are your target customers? Who are you really want to win?</li><li>What are the key needs of your target customers you want to meet?</li><li>What benifit do you provide to customers?</li><li>Who are your competitors?</li><li>What options do your customers have? the alternatives?</li><li>What is the key different between you and your competitors?</li></ul><h1 id="Decision-making-and-building-alignment"><a href="#Decision-making-and-building-alignment" class="headerlink" title="Decision-making and building alignment"></a>Decision-making and building alignment</h1><h2 id="Identify-key-milestones"><a href="#Identify-key-milestones" class="headerlink" title="Identify key milestones"></a>Identify key milestones</h2><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/Product_Milestones.3eqajoine2m0.webp"                      alt="Product Milestone" style="zoom:80%;"                 ><p>Some milestones may address the pain points of existing customers, increasing their usage and reduce the churn. And other milestones may allow your customers use your product in new ways. Some may even do not benifit your customers directly, like open new distribution channel, reducing costs.</p><ul><li>Record the strategy objectives it supports.</li><li>When you finished brainstorms your milestones, give it a priority and meet with your business leader. An one-to-one meeting may increase the chance they share true feedbacks.</li></ul><h2 id="Estimate-leves-of-effort"><a href="#Estimate-leves-of-effort" class="headerlink" title="Estimate leves of effort"></a>Estimate leves of effort</h2><ul><li>First, estimate the development capacity of your team. It usually in the form of developer days, weeks, and months.</li><li>The next is estimate the development time for each milestones. One thing we have to know is not all time is spent on developping. It may cost plenty of time to fix bugs, maintain products, and engineering.</li></ul><h2 id="Building-the-strawman-——-the-first-version"><a href="#Building-the-strawman-——-the-first-version" class="headerlink" title="Building the strawman —— the first version"></a>Building the strawman —— the first version</h2><ul><li>The first step is to roughly sequence your milestones in terms of their value in supporting your product strategy.</li><li>The next step is to schedule these milestones into your roadmap. You can start with the most basic approach to scheduling. Look at your first, highest priority milestone. Use the effort estimate provided by your product development leader,as well as the development capacity of the team, to figure out when on the calendar you could expect it to be delivered.</li><li>Next, you pick up the second highest priority milestone and assuming that the first one is completed on time, schedule that one in the same manner.</li><li>Once done, it may look like this.<br><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/Product_Milestones.3eqajoine2m0.webp"                      alt="Product Milestones"                ></li></ul><p>​        <img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/Milestone_1.74ktqexkz340.webp"                      alt="Milestones" style="zoom:80%;"                 ></p><ul><li>If these milestones are for different products,  you may separate them like this.<br><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/Product_Milestones.3eqajoine2m0.webp"                      alt="Milestone_3.png"                ></li></ul><h2 id="Here-comes-the-product-roadmap-meeting"><a href="#Here-comes-the-product-roadmap-meeting" class="headerlink" title="Here comes the product roadmap meeting"></a>Here comes the product roadmap meeting</h2><ul><li>Explain the goal</li><li>Quickly review your product strategy </li><li>Review the development capacity of your team</li><li>Walk through your product roadmap strawman</li><li>Ask the team waht they wish was different</li><li>Modify the roadmap directly, so everyone can see the consequences.</li></ul><p>This process reminds me of the RACI chart, and get all the group members in a warm meeting.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;What-is-Product-Roadmap&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#What-is-Product-Roadmap&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;What is Product Roadmap?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What is Product </summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
    <category term="Lifelong_Learning" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Lifelong-Learning/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
