<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Hexo</title>
  
  
  <link href="http://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://example.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-11-14T00:58:36.608Z</updated>
  <id>http://example.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>John Doe</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>L3_W1_2_Defining tasks and milestones</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2021/11/14/L3-W1-2-Defining-tasks-and-milestones/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2021/11/14/L3-W1-2-Defining-tasks-and-milestones/</id>
    <published>2021-11-13T16:05:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-11-14T00:58:36.608Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><u><em><strong>Project planing: put it all together. Week 1</strong></em></u></p><h1 id="Defining-tasks-and-milestones"><a href="#Defining-tasks-and-milestones" class="headerlink" title="Defining tasks and milestones"></a>Defining tasks and milestones</h1><h2 id="Understanding-tasks-and-milestones"><a href="#Understanding-tasks-and-milestones" class="headerlink" title="Understanding tasks and milestones"></a>Understanding tasks and milestones</h2><p>Milestone: an <em><strong>important point within the project schedule</strong></em> that indicates progress and usually signifies the completion of a deliverable or phase of the project.</p><p>Project task: <em><strong>an activity</strong></em> that needs to be accomplished within a set period of time.</p><p>The work of a project is broken down into many different tasks. In order to reach a milestone, my team must complete multiple tasks. For example, when we want to do a mid-term presentation about our project, tasks may include brainstorm, creating a PPT,  and practice then pre-record.Milestones and project tasks are interconnected. Tasks ladder up to milestones, which are crucial for project tracking.</p><h2 id="The-importance-of-setting-milestones"><a href="#The-importance-of-setting-milestones" class="headerlink" title="The importance of setting milestones"></a>The importance of setting milestones</h2><ul><li>***Setting milestons gives you a clear understanging of the amount of work your project will require.***When break down the project into pieces of milestones, and then you may know the amount of tasks needed to be done. Actually, it’s much more easier to think, when conducting, we will know the true amount of work.</li><li><em><strong>Keep project on track.</strong></em></li><li>***Milestones help uncover areas where you might need to adjust scope, timelines, or resources to meet your goals.***For example, if you realize that reaching a milestone will require more tasks than you’d anticipated, you might ask a stakeholder for permission to reduce the scope of the project and cut down on the number of tasks.</li><li><em><strong>Reaching milestones can seiously motivate your team, and illustrate real progress to your stakeholders.</strong></em> </li><li>Milestones also server as agreat check-in point to highlight your progress to <em><strong>stakeholders</strong></em>. Give them a clear view of what have been done and the progress is on time. Milestones must be completed on time and in sequential order</li></ul><h2 id="How-to-set-milestones"><a href="#How-to-set-milestones" class="headerlink" title="How to set milestones?"></a>How to set milestones?</h2><p><em><strong>The first step to setting a milestone is to evaluate your project as a whole.</strong></em> It helps to refer back to your project charter to remind yourself of the project goal. Then, make a list of what your team needs to do to achieve that goal.  Once you’ve determined your milestones, the next step is to assign each one a deadline. To get a good sense of timing, you can connect with teammates to discuss the tasks required to reach each milestone and get their estimates for how long these tasks will take. When you set deadlines for milestones, you will also want to consider the needs of your stakeholders.</p><h3 id="Set-tasks-to-identify-milestones"><a href="#Set-tasks-to-identify-milestones" class="headerlink" title="Set tasks to identify milestones"></a>Set tasks to identify milestones</h3><p>Setting tasks can help you clearly define milestones. You can do this in two ways:</p><ol><li><strong>Top-down scheduling:</strong> In this approach, the project manager lays out the higher-level milestones, then works to break down the effort into project tasks. The project manager works with their team to ensure that all tasks are captured.</li><li><strong>Bottom-up scheduling:</strong> In this approach, the project manager looks at all of the individual tasks that need to be completed and then rolls those tasks into manageable chunks that lead to a milestone. </li></ol><h3 id="Milestone-setting-pitfalls"><a href="#Milestone-setting-pitfalls" class="headerlink" title="Milestone-setting pitfalls"></a><strong>Milestone-setting pitfalls</strong></h3><p>Here are some things to avoid when setting milestones: </p><ul><li><strong>Don’t set too many milestones</strong>. When there are too many milestones, their importance is downplayed. And, if milestones are too small or too specific, you may end up with too many, making the project look much bigger than it really is to your team and stakeholders. </li><li><strong>Don’t mistake tasks for milestones</strong>. Remember that milestones should represent moments in time, and in order to map out how you will get to those moments, you need to assign smaller tasks to each milestone.</li><li><strong>Don’t list your milestones and tasks separately.</strong> Make sure that tasks and milestones can be visualized together in one place, such as a project plan. This will help ensure that you are hitting your deadlines and milestones. </li></ul><h2 id="Creating-a-work-breakdown-structure"><a href="#Creating-a-work-breakdown-structure" class="headerlink" title="Creating a work breakdown structure"></a>Creating a work breakdown structure</h2><h3 id="Work-Breakdown-Structure-WBS"><a href="#Work-Breakdown-Structure-WBS" class="headerlink" title="Work Breakdown Structure (WBS)"></a>Work Breakdown Structure (WBS)</h3><p>A tool that sorts the milestones and tasks of a project in a hierarchy, in the order they need to be completed.</p><p>It makes it easier to understand all of the essential project tasks, such as estimating costs, developing a schedule, assigning roles and responsibilities, and tracking progress. </p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/image-20211029100339396.1ta218aruz40.png"                      alt="WBS"                ></p><ul><li><p><strong>Start with the high-level, overarching project picture. Brainstorm with your team to list the major deliverables and milestones.</strong> Example: Imagine you are planning a company event. Your major milestones might include categories like “secure venue,” “finalize guest logistics,” and “establish agenda.”</p></li><li><p><strong>Identify the tasks that need to be performed in order to meet those milestones.</strong> Example: You could break a milestone like “secure venue” down into tasks like “research venues,” “tour and decorate space,” “make down payment,” and so on. </p></li><li><p><strong>Examine those tasks and break them down further into sub-tasks.</strong> Example: You could break down a task like “tour and decorate space” further into sub-tasks like “organize decorating committee,” “purchase decorations,” “assign decorating responsibilities,” and so on. </p></li></ul><p>Tips:</p><ul><li>To assign tasks between two or more team members with the same roles, you might take into consideration each person’s familiarity with the tasks at hand.</li><li>When assigning tasks, you should also consider each teammate’s workload.</li><li>As the project manager, you will ensure that your teammates are clear on their assigned tasks. Tool: Asana</li><li>One less obvious benefit of assigning tasks is that it creates a sense of personal responsibility for members of the team.</li><li>8/80 rule: A work package should take no less than 8 hours, and also no more than 80 hours.</li></ul><p> Further Reading: <a class="link"   href="https://www.lucidchart.com/blog/how-to-create-a-work-breakdown-structure-and-why-you-should" >How to Create a Work Breakdown Structure and Why You Should<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p>Scenario:</p><p>As a project manager for Office Green, your job includes working with the operations team to develop and implement an Operations and Training plan. Your team will use this plan for ongoing maintenance of the Plant Pals service. It will take six months to fully implement all protocols, including setting up operational tools, putting delivery processes in place, and training employees. The project will begin before the Plant Pals launch and extend beyond it.</p><p>The Operations team is responsible for managing the organization’s day-to-day business so that it continues to run smoothly. Operations provides resources to other departments, ensures consistency, and maintains the company’s profitability. The Chief Operations Officer (COO) typically leads the Operations team and works closely with other divisions, such as Sales, Client Services, Human Resources, Information Technology (IT), as well as the project manager. </p><p>Developing the Operations and Training plan marks a new stage of the project, with its own set of goals and deliverables. After assessing the requirements for the plan you determine three major milestones:</p><ul><li><em><strong>Establish a plant delivery and logistics plan</strong></em></li><li><em><strong>Select and install supply chain management software and equipment</strong></em></li><li><em><strong>Develop and launch an employee training program</strong></em></li></ul><p>For each milestone, you divide the work into three separate tasks. Each task has its own owner, duration, and details. The tasks associated with your milestones include: </p><ul><li><strong>Establish a plant delivery and logistics plan</strong>: Team members will need to source materials for packaging and hire delivery drivers. They are also responsible for calculating the delivery fees. </li><li><strong>Select and install supply chain software and equipment</strong>: Team members will supervise vendor setup of inventory management and fulfillment software. They must also supervise vendor installation of fulfillment equipment and determine internal safety protocols for the equipment.</li><li><strong>Develop and launch an employee training program</strong>: Team members will need to develop training sessions, train employees to use the software and equipment, and monitor progress and improve training processes.</li></ul><p>My trial:</p><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/11ZFVH7-HgzbNIiKM_Y7OqxhbzVTh51lzGx8UOfJB8oo/edit#slide=id.p1" >Use a WBS to create project tasks and milestones - Part 1<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1fx8Nfa2c5S8oRhKYEw2_vZ4enxRSF-DdijcccmpWtE4/edit#gid=185434937" >Use a WBS to create milestones and project tasks - Part 2<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p>Google’ reference:</p><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1MPh9B1R4AIGjfTP24mn0LF5wPbQCEbWsT_-bKf_aBxc/edit?resourcekey=0-E9l5CNEj7B3oZ-RwseXyRA#slide=id.ge7313b124a_0_0" >WBS Brainstorm Diagram<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1DesMW3hmpzocK-wQqZQ-modRzSFJYyZOQTF49J23Q08/edit#gid=0" >Use a WBS to create milestones and project tasks - Part 2<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p>The director recommend Asana as a tool to develop WBS, but not free for students outside the US right now. I think Notion can do the same thing, I will take a try.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project planing: put it all together. Week 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Defining-tasks-and-milestones&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Defini</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>L3_W1_Uderstanding the planning phase componets</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2021/11/13/L3-W1-Uderstanding-the-planning-phase-componets/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2021/11/13/L3-W1-Uderstanding-the-planning-phase-componets/</id>
    <published>2021-11-13T13:22:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-11-13T16:06:39.515Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><u><em><strong>Project planing: put it all together. Week 1</strong></em></u></p><h1 id="Uderstanding-the-planning-phase-componets"><a href="#Uderstanding-the-planning-phase-componets" class="headerlink" title="Uderstanding the planning phase componets"></a>Uderstanding the planning phase componets</h1><h2 id="The-benefits-of-planning-a-project"><a href="#The-benefits-of-planning-a-project" class="headerlink" title="The benefits of planning a project"></a>The benefits of planning a project</h2><h3 id="when-should-plan-a-project"><a href="#when-should-plan-a-project" class="headerlink" title="when should plan a project ?"></a>when should plan a project ?</h3><ul><li>Project manager gets assigned</li><li>Project goals, scope, deliveries have been approved</li><li>Team members have been assigned</li><li>Sign off on your project charter</li></ul><h3 id="What-planning-a-project-can-help"><a href="#What-planning-a-project-can-help" class="headerlink" title="What planning a project can help ?"></a>What planning a project can help ?</h3><ul><li>Understanding the work needed to achieve your goals </li><li>Coordinate efforts and timelines with other teams, contractors, and vendors</li><li>Identify and prepare for risks</li><li>Get ‘Buy-in’ from key members of the project team</li><li>Demonstrates to stakeholders that the team is taking care to start the project with a detailed plan</li></ul><h2 id="Launching-the-planning-phase"><a href="#Launching-the-planning-phase" class="headerlink" title="Launching the planning phase"></a>Launching the planning phase</h2><h3 id="What-should-be-taken-into-consideration"><a href="#What-should-be-taken-into-consideration" class="headerlink" title="What should be taken into consideration?"></a>What should be taken into consideration?</h3><ul><li><p>Schedule</p><p>The project timeline, sheich includes the start date, the end date, and dates for events in between.</p></li><li><p>Budget</p><p>The budget accounts for the total cost to complete the project. The total cost needs to be broken down to determine how much has to be spent on different elements of the project. </p></li><li><p>Risk management</p><p>Searching for possible problems related to the project and plannning ahead to mitigate these risks.</p><p>Where might the schedule get off track?</p><p>Where might the budget exceed your estimates?</p></li></ul><h3 id="Scenario"><a href="#Scenario" class="headerlink" title="Scenario"></a>Scenario</h3><p>Imagine that you’re a project manager helping a restaurant owner launch an updated menu with a few new food items at 15 locations. The owner would like you to oversee the redesign of the menu and distribution to all locations. </p><p>You’re preparing for your project’s eventual kickoff meeting. Right now, you’re thinking through the three main planning activities: building the schedule, assessing the budget, and considering potential risks. </p><ul><li><p>Schedule: The dates may include important constraints from vendors, kickoffs dates, and when to complete certain tasks. Ande a target date for the product (menu) launch, and validate that with the client. While trying to stick to the schedule, it may change during the project.</p></li><li><p>Budget: </p><ul><li>Call vendors and get quotes of items you may need to purchase.</li><li>Fees to my team members.</li><li>Fees for outside consultants or service-based vendors.</li><li>If I want to launch a website to offer ordering service, fee to develop and operate the web should also be taken into consideration.</li><li>And if the project is delayed, then what it may affect my budget? </li></ul></li><li><p>Risk management:</p><ul><li>Budget items that are likely to increase in cost. The season, politics, and natural disasters can make a difference to my contractors.</li><li>Days-off or holiday. </li><li>If team members get sick.</li><li>What about tasks and deliverables that could delay the project? </li><li>Feedback from stakeholders could also cause delays.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 id="Facilitating-a-project-kick-off-meeting"><a href="#Facilitating-a-project-kick-off-meeting" class="headerlink" title="Facilitating a project kick-off meeting"></a>Facilitating a project kick-off meeting</h2><h3 id="What-is-a-project-kick-off-meeting"><a href="#What-is-a-project-kick-off-meeting" class="headerlink" title="What is a project kick-off meeting?"></a>What is a project kick-off meeting?</h3><p>A project kickoff meeting is the first meeting in which a project team comes together to ground everyone in a shared vision, <em><strong>gain a shared understanding of the project’s goals and scope</strong></em>, and to <em><strong>understand each person’s individual roles within the team</strong></em>.</p><h3 id="Who-to-invite"><a href="#Who-to-invite" class="headerlink" title="Who to invite?"></a>Who to invite?</h3><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/18cXj5XW3FaXz_-I_cC3klzp0Hm1xJeWlrOxhXMFEXPE/edit#gid=1434934716" >RACI Chart<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><ul><li>Project team</li><li>Project stakeholders</li><li>Project sponsor</li></ul><h3 id="Why-I-need-a-kick-off-meeting"><a href="#Why-I-need-a-kick-off-meeting" class="headerlink" title="Why I need a kick-off meeting?"></a>Why I need a kick-off meeting?</h3><ul><li>Establish a shared vision</li><li>Align on scope</li><li>Build team rapport </li><li>Ask questions and offer insights</li><li>Set expectations</li></ul><p>The purpose of a kick-off meeting is to ground everyone in a shared vision, ensure they understand the project’s goals and scope, and make sure that they are all on the same page about their roles and responsibilities on the project. The kick-off meeting is critical to a project’s overall success. It gets the team together to align on goals and visions for the project and sets the project up for success.</p><h3 id="How-to-plan-a-kick-off-meeting"><a href="#How-to-plan-a-kick-off-meeting" class="headerlink" title="How to plan a kick-off meeting?"></a>How to plan a kick-off meeting?</h3><ul><li><p>Introductions</p><ul><li><p>Team member names</p></li><li><p>Project roles</p></li><li><p>Fun facts </p><p>===&gt; build team rapport</p></li></ul></li><li><p>Background </p><ul><li>How the project come to be </li><li>Why the project matters</li><li>Set a  shared vision</li></ul></li><li><p>Goals and scope</p><ul><li>In-scope</li><li>Out-of-scope</li><li>Target launch time</li><li>Milestones</li></ul></li><li><p>Roles: What work everyone is responsible for throughout the duration of the project</p></li><li><p>Collaboration</p><ul><li>Shared project tools and documents</li><li>Communication expectations e.g. daily email, weekly team check-in meeting</li></ul></li><li><p>What comes next : Set expectations and action items ==&gt; to make each teammate what actions they will need to take next.</p></li><li><p>Questions (put qs into a shared document)</p><ul><li>Gain clarity on meeting topics</li><li>Ensure the project benefits from diversity of thoughts experiences, and ideas</li></ul><p><u><em><strong>I am the man who help my teammates remove the roadblocks.</strong></em></u></p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project planing: put it all together. Week 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Uderstanding-the-planning-phase-componets&quot;&gt;&lt;a h</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
