<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Hexo</title>
  
  
  <link href="http://example.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://example.com/"/>
  <updated>2022-08-11T02:51:22.179Z</updated>
  <id>http://example.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>John Doe</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Google Data Analysis learning notes 1</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2022/08/11/Google-Data-Analysis-learning-notes-1/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2022/08/11/Google-Data-Analysis-learning-notes-1/</id>
    <published>2022-08-11T02:50:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-08-11T02:51:22.179Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Google-Data-Analysis-learning-notes-1"><a href="#Google-Data-Analysis-learning-notes-1" class="headerlink" title="Google Data Analysis learning notes 1"></a>Google Data Analysis learning notes 1</h1><h1 id="From-issue-to-action-The-six-data-analysis-phases"><a href="#From-issue-to-action-The-six-data-analysis-phases" class="headerlink" title="From issue to action: The six data analysis phases"></a>From issue to action: The six data analysis phases</h1><p>There are six data analysis phases that will help you make seamless decisions: ask, prepare, process, analyze, share, and act. Keep in mind, these are different from the data life cycle, which describes the changes data goes through over its lifetime. Let’s walk through the steps to see how they can help you solve problems you might face on the job.</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://d3c33hcgiwev3.cloudfront.net/imageAssetProxy.v1/kmiCz2A1Q7Oogs9gNbOzPQ_9d80cefae4cc434eaecaa1ad5c5025f8_DA_C1M1L2R1_A-1-.png?expiry=1660348800000&hmac=NePPvHhiuDr0ukibZrwhSj3KEsfSOFaP6XyYHoFeiQM"                      alt="Icon of a question mark with the word ask"                ></p><h2 id="Step-1-Ask"><a href="#Step-1-Ask" class="headerlink" title="Step 1: Ask"></a>Step 1: Ask</h2><p>It’s impossible to solve a problem if you don’t know what it is. These are some things to consider:</p><ul><li>Define the problem you’re trying to solve </li><li>Make sure you fully understand the stakeholder’s expectations</li><li>Focus on the actual problem and avoid any distractions</li><li>Collaborate with stakeholders and keep an open line of communication</li><li>Take a step back and see the whole situation in context</li></ul><h3 id="Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step"><a href="#Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step" class="headerlink" title="Questions to ask yourself in this step:"></a>Questions to ask yourself in this step:</h3><ol><li>What are my stakeholders saying their problems are?</li><li>Now that I’ve identified the issues, how can I help the stakeholders resolve their questions?</li></ol><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://d3c33hcgiwev3.cloudfront.net/imageAssetProxy.v1/3CybSa2UQhqsm0mtlBIaIw_ff8cf6066c4a410196171e7b36d703c4_DA_C1M1L2R1_B.png?expiry=1660348800000&hmac=_4q53DM9RKVMnk3bk7apIkTp7uyExRkLSbplrgHsMSg"                      alt="Icon of a clipboard with the word prepare"                ></p><h2 id="Step-2-Prepare"><a href="#Step-2-Prepare" class="headerlink" title="Step 2: Prepare"></a>Step 2: Prepare</h2><p>You will decide what data you need to collect in order to answer your questions and how to organize it so that it is useful. You might use your business task to decide: </p><ul><li>What metrics to measure</li><li>Locate data in your database</li><li>Create security measures to protect that data</li></ul><h3 id="Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step-1"><a href="#Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step-1" class="headerlink" title="Questions to ask yourself in this step:"></a>Questions to ask yourself in this step:</h3><ol><li>What do I need to figure out how to solve this problem?</li><li>What research do I need to do?</li></ol><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://d3c33hcgiwev3.cloudfront.net/imageAssetProxy.v1/lDcry8F7S323K8vBe7t9bg_66089daf263e4264b0a2178dba173448_DA_C1M1L2R1_C.png?expiry=1660348800000&hmac=yHLrt6HZWupUgm2EixCFBPVoPdtEkxFzr0e9TeP-0dc"                      alt="Icon of numbers with the word process"                ></p><h2 id="Step-3-Process"><a href="#Step-3-Process" class="headerlink" title="Step 3: Process"></a>Step 3: Process</h2><p>Clean data is the best data and you will need to clean up your data to get rid of any possible errors, inaccuracies, or inconsistencies. This might mean:</p><ul><li>Using spreadsheet functions to find incorrectly entered data </li><li>Using SQL functions to check for extra spaces</li><li>Removing repeated entries</li><li>Checking as much as possible for bias in the data</li></ul><h3 id="Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step-2"><a href="#Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step-2" class="headerlink" title="Questions to ask yourself in this step:"></a>Questions to ask yourself in this step:</h3><ol><li>What data errors or inaccuracies might get in my way of getting the best possible answer to the problem I am trying to solve?</li><li>How can I clean my data so the information I have is more consistent?</li></ol><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://d3c33hcgiwev3.cloudfront.net/imageAssetProxy.v1/sYq9TbgfTv2KvU24Hw79gg_da4f5051005e42779f15a718c3fbbedd_DA_C1M1L2R1_D.png?expiry=1660348800000&hmac=k9Wt1Hb_udm4HBccN-GiSp5fse4B_i7ZUd77kU8nThw"                      alt="Icon of magnifying glass with the word analyze"                ></p><h2 id="Step-4-Analyze"><a href="#Step-4-Analyze" class="headerlink" title="Step 4: Analyze"></a>Step 4: Analyze</h2><p>You will want to think analytically about your data. At this stage, you might sort and format your data to make it easier to: </p><ul><li>Perform calculations</li><li>Combine data from multiple sources</li><li>Create tables with your results</li></ul><h3 id="Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step-3"><a href="#Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step-3" class="headerlink" title="Questions to ask yourself in this step:"></a>Questions to ask yourself in this step:</h3><ol><li>What story is my data telling me?</li><li>How will my data help me solve this problem?</li><li>Who needs my company’s product or service? What type of person is most likely to use it?</li></ol><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://d3c33hcgiwev3.cloudfront.net/imageAssetProxy.v1/ioCuqp2VT6OArqqdlU-jdQ_30fd6216552a49ef85ffd629ae596f4c_DA_C1M1L2R1_E.png?expiry=1660348800000&hmac=2w4dUGOCJRtAv0mkBlErgSuaepoq7Q6vjqm9x3sPzVU"                      alt="Icon of an arrow with the word share"                ></p><h2 id="Step-5-Share"><a href="#Step-5-Share" class="headerlink" title="Step 5: Share"></a>Step 5: Share</h2><p>Everyone shares their results differently so be sure to summarize your results with clear and enticing visuals of your analysis using data via tools like graphs or dashboards. This is your chance to show the stakeholders you have solved their problem and how you got there. Sharing will certainly help your team: </p><ul><li>Make better decisions</li><li>Make more informed decisions</li><li>Lead to stronger outcomes</li><li>Successfully communicate your findings</li></ul><h3 id="Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step-4"><a href="#Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step-4" class="headerlink" title="Questions to ask yourself in this step:"></a>Questions to ask yourself in this step:</h3><ol><li>How can I make what I present to the stakeholders engaging and easy to understand?</li><li>What would help me understand this if I were the listener?</li></ol><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://d3c33hcgiwev3.cloudfront.net/imageAssetProxy.v1/rWF6jetqTPiheo3rapz48w_cd4afb997b9d449a89223dab279f8f09_DA_C1M1L2R1_F.png?expiry=1660348800000&hmac=mu7NiSmgxSMyo2QZpCIUswgGx5hTqNPtGoDqjR9h_7c"                      alt="Icon of finger pressing on a button with the word act"                ></p><h2 id="Step-6-Act"><a href="#Step-6-Act" class="headerlink" title="Step 6: Act"></a>Step 6: Act</h2><p>Now it’s time to act on your data. You will take everything you have learned from your data analysis and put it to use. This could mean providing your stakeholders with recommendations based on your findings so they can make data-driven decisions.</p><h3 id="Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step-5"><a href="#Questions-to-ask-yourself-in-this-step-5" class="headerlink" title="Questions to ask yourself in this step:"></a>Questions to ask yourself in this step:</h3><ol><li>How can I use the feedback I received during the share phase (step 5) to actually meet the stakeholder’s needs and expectations?</li></ol><p>These six steps can help you to break the data analysis process into smaller, manageable parts, which is called <strong>structured thinking</strong>. This process involves four basic activities:</p><ol><li>Recognizing the current problem or situation</li><li>Organizing available information </li><li>Revealing gaps and opportunities</li><li>Identifying your options</li></ol><p>When you are starting out in your career as a data analyst, it is normal to feel pulled in a few different directions with your role and expectations. Following processes like the ones outlined here and using structured thinking skills can help get you back on track, fill in any gaps and let you know exactly what you need.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;Google-Data-Analysis-learning-notes-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Google-Data-Analysis-learning-notes-1&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Google Data Analys</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Data Analysis" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Data-Analysis/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why I love Coursera</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2022/08/03/Why-I-love-Coursera/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2022/08/03/Why-I-love-Coursera/</id>
    <published>2022-08-03T05:58:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-08-04T07:11:52.481Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="What-is-my-favourite-application"><a href="#What-is-my-favourite-application" class="headerlink" title="What is my favourite application?"></a>What is my favourite application?</h1><p>Today, I realized I spent more than 10 hours on Coursera every week for the past year and I really enjoyed this platform. Coursera is a platform that you can build skills with online courses from top institutions and universities. I like it since I can learn a lot from top universities whenever and wherever I am, no time, places limits at a low cost or even free. I learnt a lot  courses on it and I really want to introduce it to you. </p><h1 id="How-did-I-know-Coursera"><a href="#How-did-I-know-Coursera" class="headerlink" title="How did I know Coursera?"></a>How did I know Coursera?</h1><p>I still remember the first time I met Coursera when I was learning Deep Learning taught by Andrew Ng, who was a famous professor in Stanford University. At the end of his class in deeplearning.ai, he would introduce us Coursera created by Daphne Koller and himself. MOOC (Massive Open Online Courses) was bringing educational and vocational courses online and Coursera totally won my fragemental time on PC. Similarly, Weixin Reading introduced online reading to the public in China, and became the most visited app on my phone when I was free. </p><h2 id="What-is-the-customer-journey-map"><a href="#What-is-the-customer-journey-map" class="headerlink" title="What is the customer journey map?"></a>What is the customer journey map?</h2><p>The general process of an individual user can be divided into the following steps.</p><ul><li>Log in as individual user or enterprise users</li><li>Find the courses you want by searching jobs, skills, or universities</li><li>Read the introduction of the course and enroll</li><li>Take the course with your customize schedule</li><li>Take all discussions, tests, peer value, and quiz</li><li>Earn a certificate provided by Coursera and institutions</li><li>Share your learning and certificates to LinkedIn or other platforms</li></ul><h1 id="Business-model-of-Coursera"><a href="#Business-model-of-Coursera" class="headerlink" title="Business model of Coursera"></a>Business model of Coursera</h1><h2 id="Who-are-the-customers-Customer-Segments"><a href="#Who-are-the-customers-Customer-Segments" class="headerlink" title="Who are the customers? (Customer Segments)"></a>Who are the customers? (Customer Segments)</h2><p>Coursera provides services to two main kinds customer segments. The first one is educational institutions like universitties and companies, which wants to share course resources with a fully access. The other one can be the end-users who want to learn some skills in specific fields but may find it difficult to get access to educational resources. </p><p>The following types of people can be their potential end-users:</p><ul><li>High school students who want to take college courses in advance.</li><li>College students who want to take online courses rather than offline courses.</li><li>College students who want to learn extracurricular skills.</li><li>Fresh graduate students who want to decide or change career path.</li><li>People who already have a job want to strengthen their existing knowledge.</li><li>People who already have jobs and want to learn new skills.</li></ul><p>Try to imagine this scenario: more and more people realize the importance of life-long learning. As a fresh graduate, Allen is pursuing  a full-time job related to product management, business development. For a better fit, he chooses courses related to digital product managemt, Data analysis, and project managemtn on Coursera and spends 10 hours per week on it. </p><h2 id="What-value-does-Coursera-deliver-to-customers-Value-Propositions"><a href="#What-value-does-Coursera-deliver-to-customers-Value-Propositions" class="headerlink" title="What value does Coursera deliver to customers? (Value Propositions)"></a>What value does Coursera deliver to customers? (Value Propositions)</h2><p>When it comes to what customer needs Coursera want to satisfy, it allows end-users like me easy and complete access to top educational online resources that  many constomers may find unaffordable or inaccessable through its website and application.</p><p>Sharing high-level courses also means that universities and insititutions can reach a greater number of consumers more easily, futhering their individual brand identities. </p><h2 id="How-does-Coursera-make-money-Revenue-Streams"><a href="#How-does-Coursera-make-money-Revenue-Streams" class="headerlink" title="How does Coursera make money? (Revenue Streams)"></a>How does Coursera make money? (Revenue Streams)</h2><p>Courserea starts its journey with the goal of providing high-level education resources for free to anyone looking for it. Now, Coursera charges from several channels to improve its services. </p><h3 id="Free-access"><a href="#Free-access" class="headerlink" title="Free access"></a>Free access</h3><p>There are many ways to get access to some courses for free since some courses are provided to everyone for free. Besides that,  people can choose audition when choose whether to pay for the course so that  they still have access to most course materials for this course without a certificate.</p><h3 id="Certificates"><a href="#Certificates" class="headerlink" title="Certificates"></a>Certificates</h3><p>Most courses are offered with no charge. However, people who want to earn a certificate of completion which is a trusted and shareable way to showcase their new skills can choose to pay the course fee. This feature was landed in 2013, giving paying students access to graded assignments, homework, and examinations. If completed satisfactorily, they can earn a verified certificate at the end of the course, and they can visit the course in the future with no limits. The course fee varies between from <strong>$39</strong> to <strong>$89</strong> depending on the course. Nowadays, people can choose to be a membership with no limits to a sea of courses at a cost of <strong>$39</strong> per month. </p><p>If you have planty time during some period so that you can finish the course within the7-days trail, once finished, you can also get the certificate and have no limits when revisit the course in the future.</p><h3 id="Specializations"><a href="#Specializations" class="headerlink" title="Specializations"></a>Specializations</h3><p>This feature is a bundle of different but related courses designed to help customers  deepen their expertise in a specific area. For example, DeFi: The future Finance Specialization consisted of 4 courses aims to provide learners a much deeper understanding of both the infrastructure of DeFi and leading applications. Customers can pay monthly subscription fees between <strong>$39</strong> to <strong>$89</strong>, depending on the specialization, for access to all resources and specialization certificates.</p><h3 id="Coursera-for-Business"><a href="#Coursera-for-Business" class="headerlink" title="Coursera for Business"></a>Coursera for Business</h3><p>Coursera for Business enables businesses to offer their employees or teams access to a sea of courses to boost their expertise. Compared to traditional certificates, Coursera provides this service with a lower fee of <strong>$400</strong> per employee per year. Enterprise packages comes with higher cost than personal or teams’ plan. Coursera for Campus provides silimar option to the government and universities.</p><p>Since higher price and growing customers in this segment, it has quickly become a key channel of revenue.</p><h3 id="University-Degrees"><a href="#University-Degrees" class="headerlink" title="University Degrees"></a>University Degrees</h3><p>Collaborated with top universities world wide, Coursera offers students a chance to complete a fully recognized Bachelor’s or Master’s Degree, including MBA from UIUC. The price is far lower compared to degrees in campus, but with the same instructors who teach in person. Scholarships are provided. It’s reported that Coursera generated <a href="(https://s27.q4cdn.com/928340662/files/doc_financials/2021/q1/COUR_Earnings-Infographic_Q1-FY21.pdf)">$12.0M</a> in revenue in Q1, 2021 with 13,493 students enrolled. </p><h1 id="Competitve-analysis"><a href="#Competitve-analysis" class="headerlink" title="Competitve analysis"></a>Competitve analysis</h1><h2 id="SWOT-Analysis"><a href="#SWOT-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="SWOT Analysis"></a>SWOT Analysis</h2><h3 id="Strength"><a href="#Strength" class="headerlink" title="Strength"></a>Strength</h3><ul><li>Strong relationships with its key partners to offer colourful and high-level courses.</li><li>First-move advantages: kind of becoming market standard. After Coursera, many universities or educational angency like MOOC China, and MIT opensource, built their own platform which follows these standards. What’s more, the earlier Coursera ran into the market, the bigger market share it would take. Some MOOC platforms like Xue Tang Zai Xian created by Chinese government and universities has limited market usually in domestic rather than a golbal market. </li><li>Good environment to spread courses. Multi-lanuage courses are provided to learners from all over the world. At the same time, Coursera advocates learners to take part in translation event so that subttitle will be translate into their mother language and would be offered after reviews.</li><li>Diverse revenue channels. Multiple revenue model enables Couresera great resources to not only keep competitve to the threat of newcomers but also invest into R&amp;D.</li></ul><h3 id="Weakness"><a href="#Weakness" class="headerlink" title="Weakness"></a>Weakness</h3><ul><li>Services Coursera provided are more focus on solution space, which means more about what can they do. Sometimes they ignore the interests of external stakeholders.</li><li>Poor visual design. Terrible design on both Andriod and iPhone.</li></ul><h3 id="Opportunities"><a href="#Opportunities" class="headerlink" title="Opportunities"></a>Opportunities</h3><ul><li>Covid-19 has changed many people’s lifestyle. Some universities promoted hybrid teaching model, and sea of students were trying to get access to online learning. Even after Covid, people really enjoy online learning since they can follow their own schedule.</li><li>Globalization enables Coursera more international markets. Growth in international market can also help Coursera diversify the risk as it will be less dependent on domestic market for revenue.</li><li>Technology empowering more possibilities. With the development and application of Machine Learning and AI, more smart features including recommendation can be offered to keep customers active.</li></ul><h3 id="Threats"><a href="#Threats" class="headerlink" title="Threats"></a>Threats</h3><ul><li>Government Regulations. Coursera should keep a close eye on the fast changing government regulations under the growing conflicts environment .</li><li>Customers are moving toward mobile  which can hamper the growth as Coursera  still hasn’t got a comprehensive mobile strategy.</li></ul><h1 id="What-can-be-improved"><a href="#What-can-be-improved" class="headerlink" title="What can be improved?"></a>What can be improved?</h1><h2 id="Nice-improvements-from-my-experiences"><a href="#Nice-improvements-from-my-experiences" class="headerlink" title="Nice improvements from my experiences"></a>Nice improvements from my experiences</h2><p>As a customer, although Coursera provides great services,  for more effience and easy of use, some nice improvments can be the following:</p><ul><li><p><strong>A calendar that shows due dates for assignments and quizzes across all of your courses</strong>. When I signed up for 3-4 classes, it’s hard to keep track of what is due and when. Optional email reminders would be a nice touch.</p></li><li><p><strong>Quick feedbacks and colorful interations to keep users active.</strong> Solving small but not so primitive tasks by students could help feeling the progress. And the more types of such quizzes are presented (not just a multiple choice), the more learners will be willing to join. What’s more, peer value and discussion can be offered for students to communicate more to help each other so that they will spend more time on it to get a better understanding and build the willing to learn other related courses.</p></li><li><p><strong>Better interaction design on Mobile application.</strong> A terrible journey starts when open Coursea on both Android and iPhone. It’s difficult for me to get what I want.</p></li><li><p><strong>Better recommendation performance.</strong> Sometimes, after finishing one course, if learners want a deep understanding of specific field, a good recommendation at the end of learning will keep them engaged.</p></li></ul><p>More testing should be conducted so that we can learn from the feedbacks from users and provide higher-perforance services.</p><h2 id="Future-plan"><a href="#Future-plan" class="headerlink" title="Future plan"></a>Future plan</h2><p>Some plans can be taken into consideration for further marketing.</p><ul><li>Conduct geographic analysis to move to new markets.</li><li>Conduct IP analysis to keep competition out of the door.</li><li> Invest more in building an easy-use mobile application.</li><li>Keep existing customers active so that improve their customers life value. Some nice try can be introducing a new product or service of Coursera to existing customers, improving interaction and visual design.</li><li>Improve customer loyalty of Coursera Coursera’s customers. Marketing efforts can be used to increase loyalty among existing customers by organizing events, and by providing post purchase information and services.</li><li>Increase brand awareness. Features like stronger and multiple sharing channels can reach new audiences on social media. What’s more, newcomers have a better chance of choosing a course through a friend’s recommendation.</li></ul><p>More info and market analysis should be conducted to build a good strategy. Will be added soon.</p><h1 id="Thank-you-for-your-time"><a href="#Thank-you-for-your-time" class="headerlink" title="Thank you for your time : )"></a>Thank you for your time : )</h1>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;What-is-my-favourite-application&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#What-is-my-favourite-application&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;What is my favourite applica</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
    <category term="Business Model" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Business-Model/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>如何在Mac上使用Hexo开启博客之旅</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2022/01/12/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%9C%A8Mac%E4%B8%8A%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8Hexo%E5%BC%80%E5%90%AF%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2%E4%B9%8B%E6%97%85/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2022/01/12/%E5%A6%82%E4%BD%95%E5%9C%A8Mac%E4%B8%8A%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8Hexo%E5%BC%80%E5%90%AF%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2%E4%B9%8B%E6%97%85/</id>
    <published>2022-01-12T01:43:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T08:09:13.422Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>之前使用了搭建在阿里云的轻量级服务器中的WordPress开启了我的第一个博客，可是由于使用起来体验不好，困扰我的可能有以下几点：</p><ol><li>使用阿里云轻量级服务器的过程中，一直出现服务器或数据库连接错误的情况。</li><li>在国内的域名需要备案，出国后就希望能够开启一个比较宽松自由的风格。</li><li>我的需求很简单，只是需要有个简洁的地方写点小东西罢了，倘或碰巧被你看见了，那便是我的幸运吧。虽然WordPress可以提供非常丰富的功能，但是嘞，对我来说有些 ‘乱花渐欲迷人眼’。</li></ol><p>于是转到了使用Hexo + Github Pages的静态博客组合，简单明了。</p><h1 id="什么是Hexo呢？"><a href="#什么是Hexo呢？" class="headerlink" title="什么是Hexo呢？"></a>什么是Hexo呢？</h1><p><a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/zh-cn/" >Hexo<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> 是一个快速、简洁且高效的博客框架。嗯，有道理，我喜欢。感兴趣的可以在官网上自行查看更多介绍。</p><h1 id="如何配置环境"><a href="#如何配置环境" class="headerlink" title="如何配置环境"></a>如何配置环境</h1><p>安装 Hexo 相当简单，只需要先安装下列应用程序即可：</p><ul><li><p><a class="link"   href="http://nodejs.org/" >Node.js<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> </p><p>使用使用 <a class="link"   href="https://brew.sh/" >Homebrew<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>安装</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ brew install node</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></li><li><p><a class="link"   href="http://git-scm.com/" >Git<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p>使用 <a class="link"   href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/" >Homebrew<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>, <a class="link"   href="http://www.macports.org/" >MacPorts<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> 或者下载 <a class="link"   href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/git-osx-installer/" >安装程序<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>。</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ brew install git</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></li></ul><ul><li><p>安装Hexo</p><p>所有必备的应用程序安装完成后，即可使用 npm 安装 Hexo。</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ npm install -g hexo-cli</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure></li></ul><h1 id="如何搭建博客"><a href="#如何搭建博客" class="headerlink" title="如何搭建博客"></a>如何搭建博客</h1><ol><li><p>在你喜欢的地方建立一个名字为 ‘blog’ 的文件夹（名字也可按你喜欢的来）</p></li><li><p>进入blog文件夹：<code>cd blog</code></p></li><li><p>初始化：<code>hexo init</code></p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/hexo.1u14tv7unpxc.webp"                      alt="hexo" style="zoom:80%;"                 ></li><li><p>启动Hexo：<code>hexo s</code></p><p>之后会出现一个默认的博文，浏览器输入：<a class="link"   href="http://localhost:4000/" >http://localhost:4000<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>，便可查看。</p></li><li><p>新建一篇博文：<code>hexo n &#39;如何在Mac上使用Hexo开启博客之旅&#39;</code></p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/hexo-n.1qlk84t6ch5s.webp"                      alt="hexo-n"                ></p></li></ol><p>​    接下来就在自己喜欢的编辑器里编写吧，我自己使用过Vscode、Typora、以及Obsidian等来写Markdown以及管理自己的笔记。个人推荐Typora：界面简洁，所见即所得。Typora最近开始收费喽，大家看看自己的荷包吧，Obsidian目前仍然免费，但是功能强大，适合建立自己的知识网络，用来写博客是在大材小用。</p><ol start="6"><li><p>在写完后，同样进入到blog文件夹下，运行</p><p>清理：<code>hexo clean</code></p><p>启动：<code>hexo g</code></p><p>生成：<code>hexo s</code></p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/hexo-s.3j4892swnoe0.webp"                      alt="hexo-s"                ></p><p>再次进入<a class="link"   href="http://localhost:4000/" >http://localhost:4000<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>，便可查看你写好的博客了</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/blog.70psm0hpv200.webp"                      alt="blog"                ></p></li></ol><p>到这里搭建博客就已经成功了，接下来是将博客部署到Github上</p><h1 id="Hexo-Github"><a href="#Hexo-Github" class="headerlink" title="Hexo + Github"></a>Hexo + Github</h1><ol><li>**登录github：<a class="link"   href="https://github.com/" >https://github.com<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>，没账号的新建一个，新创建一个仓库New repository，仓库名必须为：<code>昵称.github.io</code>:**，输入描述，创建：</li></ol><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/github.5adlppym0i00.webp"                      alt="github" style="zoom:50%;"                 ><p>​                在这里因为我已经创建过了，所以会显示已经存在账户。</p><ol start="2"><li><p>接着回答terminal中，crtl + c 结束之前的运行，依旧在blog文件夹下部署github的插件：<code>npm install hexo-deployer-git --save</code></p></li><li><p>接着更改blog文件夹下面**_config.yml**的配置，如下</p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/blog2.65i7zq6f44c0.webp"                      alt="blog2"                ></p></li></ol><p>​        可以从这里复制：</p><figure class="highlight plaintext"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">deploy:</span><br><span class="line">  type: git</span><br><span class="line">  repo: https://github.com/AllenZhuer/AllenZhuer.github.io.git</span><br><span class="line">  branch: master</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><ol start="4"><li>最后回到terminal，使用 <code>hexo d</code> 将博客部署到远端。中间会让输入github密码，输入即可，后续部署完成，即可访问你的远端地址。例子就是这样的: <a class="link"   href="https://allenzhuer.github.io/" >https://allenzhuer.github.io/<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></li></ol><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/Xnip2022-01-12_15-51-30.7aop23brb5k0.webp"                      alt="Xnip2022-01-12_15-51-30"                ></p><p>这里呢，由于我使用了主题可能会和你的页面有一些差异，不过也没有问题，接下来我们将开始部署主题。</p><h1 id="选个喜欢的主题吧"><a href="#选个喜欢的主题吧" class="headerlink" title="选个喜欢的主题吧"></a>选个喜欢的主题吧</h1><ol><li>最重要的就是选主题了：<a class="link"   href="https://hexo.io/themes/%EF%BC%8C" >https://hexo.io/themes/，<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> 超多主题随你选择。</li></ol><p>我选择的主题为 <a class="link"   href="https://keep-docs.xpoet.cn/" >keep<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>，里面有非常详细的介绍，请移步吧。</p><ol start="2"><li>铛铛，部署完主题后，别忘了它们：</li></ol><p>清理：<code>hexo clean</code></p><p>启动：<code>hexo g</code></p><p>生成：<code>hexo s</code></p><p>部署：<code>hexo d</code></p><p>部署之后，可能有一点点延迟，等一小会儿就行了，捏一捏桌子上的小黄鸭吧。</p><p>如果在你的博客中发现图片加载较慢的问题，推荐一个图床平台 <a class="link"   href="https://picx.xpoet.cn/#/upload" >Picx<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> , 希望能够帮到你。</p><h1 id="域名"><a href="#域名" class="headerlink" title="域名"></a>域名</h1><p>最后一步是购买一个自己喜欢的域名，因为我思来想去的域名已经被别人购买了，并且也没有抱有此博客被许多人看到的想法，所以域名购买暂时告一段落。等到哪天域名过期或者是想到新的域名再来继续更新吧。</p><p>一些购买域名的网站推荐：<a class="link"   href="https://www.tkqlhce.com/jg117mu2-u1HQNLIIIIHJLKORNNO" >NameCheap<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> , <a class="link"   href="https://www.kqzyfj.com/r975xdmjdl09641111021627938" >Godaddy<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> , <a class="link"   href="https://www.namesilo.com/?rid=791ee74iy" >Namesilo<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a> 等等。</p><p>如果这篇博客恰巧被你看到并且对你有帮助的话，我将十分开心。</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;之前使用了搭建在阿里云的轻量级服务器中的WordPress开启了我的第一个博客，可是由于使用起来体验不好，困扰我的可能有以下几点：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;使用阿里云轻量级服务器的过程中，一直出现服务器或数据库连接错误的情况。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在国内的域名需要备案，出国</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="blog" scheme="http://example.com/tags/blog/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What is a Product Roadmap?</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2022/01/12/What-is-a-Product-Roadmap/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2022/01/12/What-is-a-Product-Roadmap/</id>
    <published>2022-01-12T01:04:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-12T01:35:18.787Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="What-is-Product-Roadmap"><a href="#What-is-Product-Roadmap" class="headerlink" title="What is Product Roadmap?"></a>What is Product Roadmap?</h1><p>Product Roadmap is a long-term product development plan that gives all product stakeholders the infomation they need to coordinate plans.</p><h2 id="Why-we-need-a-Product-Roadmap"><a href="#Why-we-need-a-Product-Roadmap" class="headerlink" title="Why we need a Product Roadmap?"></a>Why we need a Product Roadmap?</h2><p>A product roadmap provides a prediction to the product development process.</p><h2 id="Who-are-your-product-stakeholders"><a href="#Who-are-your-product-stakeholders" class="headerlink" title="Who are your product stakeholders?"></a>Who are your product stakeholders?</h2><ul><li>Customers</li><li>Customers-facing groups like sales, marketing, and customer support</li><li>Investors, and sponsors</li><li>Architects, designers, and engineers.</li><li>Human resources</li><li>Legal team</li><li>……</li></ul><h2 id="We-need-both-Product-backlog-and-Product-roadmap"><a href="#We-need-both-Product-backlog-and-Product-roadmap" class="headerlink" title="We need both Product backlog and Product roadmap."></a>We need both Product backlog and Product roadmap.</h2><ul><li>You estimate the dates of the product milestones on the roadmap using a completely independent set of top-down estimates from your product development leader. In the end, these estimates are inaccurate, of course. But as long as they’re close, they’ll serve the purposes of the product roadmap, to allow coordination among the different product stakeholders. Increasingly, your backlog will be directed by the product roadmap,which is one of the main ways you ensure that the activities of the product development team are aligned with the needs and goals of the whole company.<h1 id="Laying-the-grooundwork"><a href="#Laying-the-grooundwork" class="headerlink" title="Laying the grooundwork"></a>Laying the grooundwork</h1><h2 id="Why-the-process-is-important"><a href="#Why-the-process-is-important" class="headerlink" title="Why the process is important?"></a>Why the process is important?</h2></li><li> <em><strong>A roadmap has no value if the stakeholders are not aligned in advance.</strong></em></li><li> <em><strong>The fail usually comes from engineers, designers, and the whole team not being exposed to the project early.</strong></em><h2 id="What-are-the-product-development-purposes"><a href="#What-are-the-product-development-purposes" class="headerlink" title="What are the product development purposes?"></a>What are the product development purposes?</h2></li><li>Serve the business.</li><li>Support overall business strategy.</li><li>Win customer adoption, loyalty.</li><li>Generate revenue.<h2 id="How-to-create-alignment"><a href="#How-to-create-alignment" class="headerlink" title="How to create alignment?"></a>How to create alignment?</h2></li><li>Include stakeholders early.</li><li>Ask for, address, feedback.</li><li>Send updates.<h2 id="What-a-successful-Roadmap-need"><a href="#What-a-successful-Roadmap-need" class="headerlink" title="What a successful Roadmap need?"></a>What a successful Roadmap need?</h2></li><li>Sound strategy.</li><li>Realistic.</li><li>Fully supported.<h2 id="How-to-avoid-failures"><a href="#How-to-avoid-failures" class="headerlink" title="How to avoid failures?"></a>How to avoid failures?</h2></li><li>Spend time with stakeholders at the beginning of the process.</li><li>Ask for underlying thoughts.</li><li>Explain the importance of including others.</li><li>Estimate the development time.<h2 id="Select-your-stakeholders"><a href="#Select-your-stakeholders" class="headerlink" title="Select your stakeholders"></a>Select your stakeholders</h2></li><li>Business leader: allocate the resources and prioritize the tasks are necessary to the product sucess.</li><li>Sales leader: They have the target to hit. And they have the ability to rally resources to make the roadmap sucessful.</li><li>Product development leader: They are response for organizing and motivting their team to hit the roadmap milestones.</li><li>When working across groups, use the sales leader as the your business leader.</li></ul><h2 id="Customers-research"><a href="#Customers-research" class="headerlink" title="Customers research"></a>Customers research</h2><p>There are some question have to figure out:</p><ul><li>What decisions do your customer need to make in choosing your product?</li><li>What problem are they trying to solve?</li><li>What other options are available to them?</li></ul><p>And luckily,  there are some ways you can get to your customers:</p><ul><li>Initiate a research group.</li><li>Ask your customer yourself like make an appointment, a phone call, a zoom meeting, etc. Reach out to your customers directly may be the best way to get insights.</li><li>Participate in sales or customer service meetings.</li></ul><h2 id="Start-with-product-strategy"><a href="#Start-with-product-strategy" class="headerlink" title="Start with product strategy"></a>Start with product strategy</h2><p>A product strategy describes how your company will achieve its business goals. And a product strategy should answer the following questions:</p><ul><li>What are your goals?</li><li>How will you measure your sucess?</li><li>Who are your target customers? Who are you really want to win?</li><li>What are the key needs of your target customers you want to meet?</li><li>What benifit do you provide to customers?</li><li>Who are your competitors?</li><li>What options do your customers have? the alternatives?</li><li>What is the key different between you and your competitors?</li></ul><h1 id="Decision-making-and-building-alignment"><a href="#Decision-making-and-building-alignment" class="headerlink" title="Decision-making and building alignment"></a>Decision-making and building alignment</h1><h2 id="Identify-key-milestones"><a href="#Identify-key-milestones" class="headerlink" title="Identify key milestones"></a>Identify key milestones</h2><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/Product_Milestones.3eqajoine2m0.webp"                      alt="Product Milestone" style="zoom:80%;"                 ><p>Some milestones may address the pain points of existing customers, increasing their usage and reduce the churn. And other milestones may allow your customers use your product in new ways. Some may even do not benifit your customers directly, like open new distribution channel, reducing costs.</p><ul><li>Record the strategy objectives it supports.</li><li>When you finished brainstorms your milestones, give it a priority and meet with your business leader. An one-to-one meeting may increase the chance they share true feedbacks.</li></ul><h2 id="Estimate-leves-of-effort"><a href="#Estimate-leves-of-effort" class="headerlink" title="Estimate leves of effort"></a>Estimate leves of effort</h2><ul><li>First, estimate the development capacity of your team. It usually in the form of developer days, weeks, and months.</li><li>The next is estimate the development time for each milestones. One thing we have to know is not all time is spent on developping. It may cost plenty of time to fix bugs, maintain products, and engineering.</li></ul><h2 id="Building-the-strawman-——-the-first-version"><a href="#Building-the-strawman-——-the-first-version" class="headerlink" title="Building the strawman —— the first version"></a>Building the strawman —— the first version</h2><ul><li>The first step is to roughly sequence your milestones in terms of their value in supporting your product strategy.</li><li>The next step is to schedule these milestones into your roadmap. You can start with the most basic approach to scheduling. Look at your first, highest priority milestone. Use the effort estimate provided by your product development leader,as well as the development capacity of the team, to figure out when on the calendar you could expect it to be delivered.</li><li>Next, you pick up the second highest priority milestone and assuming that the first one is completed on time, schedule that one in the same manner.</li><li>Once done, it may look like this.<br><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/Product_Milestones.3eqajoine2m0.webp"                      alt="Product Milestones"                ></li></ul><p>​        <img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/Milestone_1.74ktqexkz340.webp"                      alt="Milestones" style="zoom:80%;"                 ></p><ul><li>If these milestones are for different products,  you may separate them like this.<br><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/Product_Milestones.3eqajoine2m0.webp"                      alt="Milestone_3.png"                ></li></ul><h2 id="Here-comes-the-product-roadmap-meeting"><a href="#Here-comes-the-product-roadmap-meeting" class="headerlink" title="Here comes the product roadmap meeting"></a>Here comes the product roadmap meeting</h2><ul><li>Explain the goal</li><li>Quickly review your product strategy </li><li>Review the development capacity of your team</li><li>Walk through your product roadmap strawman</li><li>Ask the team waht they wish was different</li><li>Modify the roadmap directly, so everyone can see the consequences.</li></ul><p>This process reminds me of the RACI chart, and get all the group members in a warm meeting.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;What-is-Product-Roadmap&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#What-is-Product-Roadmap&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;What is Product Roadmap?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What is Product </summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Notes/"/>
    
    <category term="Lifelong_Learning" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Lifelong-Learning/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>C3_W2_P3_Utilizing tools to build a project plan</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2021/11/27/C3-W2-P3-Utilizing-tools-to-build-a-project-plan/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2021/11/27/C3-W2-P3-Utilizing-tools-to-build-a-project-plan/</id>
    <published>2021-11-27T12:13:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-11-27T12:16:55.997Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em><strong><u>Week2 Building a project plan part 3</u></strong></em> </p><p><em><strong>Course link</strong></em> : <a class="link"   href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/project-planning-google/home/welcome" >Project Planning: Putting It All Together<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><h1 id="Utilizing-tools-to-build-a-project-plan"><a href="#Utilizing-tools-to-build-a-project-plan" class="headerlink" title="Utilizing tools to build a project plan"></a>Utilizing tools to build a project plan</h1><h2 id="Developing-a-project-schedule"><a href="#Developing-a-project-schedule" class="headerlink" title="Developing a project schedule"></a>Developing a project schedule</h2><p>An anchor of a good project plan is a clear schedule containing all the tasks of a project, their owners, and when they need to be completed. </p><p>Gantt chart: A horizontal bar chart that maps out a project schedule. It’s a highly visual representation of a projects tasks with clear breakdowns of who’s responsible for the work and when those tasks are due.</p><h2 id="Practice-estimate-a-project-plan-by-creating-a-Gantt-chart"><a href="#Practice-estimate-a-project-plan-by-creating-a-Gantt-chart" class="headerlink" title="Practice: estimate a project plan by creating a Gantt chart."></a>Practice: estimate a project plan by creating a Gantt chart.</h2><h3 id="Scenario-Plant-Pals-project-for-Office-Green"><a href="#Scenario-Plant-Pals-project-for-Office-Green" class="headerlink" title="Scenario: Plant Pals project for Office Green"></a>Scenario: Plant Pals project for Office Green</h3><ul><li>Your team will use the plan for ongoing maintenance of the Plant Pals service.</li><li>It will take six months to fully implement all protocols, including setting up operational tools, putting delivery processes in place, and training employees.</li><li>The project will begin before the Plant Pals launch and extend beyond it.</li></ul><p>Your team for this stage of the project includes the following roles:</p><ul><li>A <strong>Financial Analyst,</strong> who tracks and calculates costs and revenue</li><li>A <strong>Fulfillment Director</strong>, who sources materials, confirms fulfillment processes are correctly implemented, and ensures equipment is functional (with the help of the Quality Assurance Tester)</li><li>An <strong>Inventory Manager</strong>, who maintains inventory and oversees software installation </li><li>A <strong>Human Resources Specialist</strong>, who manages hiring and develops training protocols (with the help of the Training Manager)</li><li>A <strong>Training Manager</strong>, who reports to the HR Specialist, runs the training program on the established protocols, and refines training processes</li><li>A <strong>Quality Assurance Tester</strong>, who ensures product quality and determines safety protocols and best practices </li></ul><p><strong>Milestone 1: Establish a plant delivery and logistics plan</strong></p><ul><li>Source packaging materials. This task will take 10 business days (March 1st to March 12th).</li><li>Hire delivery drivers. This process will also take ten business days (March 15th to March 26th).</li><li>Calculate the delivery fees. This task will also take 10 business days (March 29th to April 9th). </li></ul><p><strong>Milestone 2: Select and install supply chain software and equipment</strong></p><ul><li>Supervise vendor setup of inventory management and fulfillment software. This process will take three business days (April 12th to April 14th). </li><li>Supervise vendor installation of the fulfillment equipment from April 15th to April 16th (two business days). </li><li>Determine internal safety protocols for the equipment from April 19th to April 30th (10 business days). </li></ul><p><strong>Milestone 3: Develop and launch an employee training program</strong></p><ul><li>Develop training sessions. This task will take 10 business days (May 3rd to May 14th).</li><li>Train employees to use the software and equipment. The training sessions will take place over 10 business days (May 17th to May 28th). </li><li>Monitor employee progress and improve training processes. This process will last for 10 business days (May 31st to June 11th).</li></ul><p>Here is my work: <a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1ca4-aCuXnM6gPPXsWvfZ95TKoWbXZv9weTXG8w2N-ag/edit?usp=sharing" >Gantt chart<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><h2 id="Project-plan-best-practices"><a href="#Project-plan-best-practices" class="headerlink" title="Project plan best practices"></a>Project plan best practices</h2><p>How can you help make sure that your plan works for you and your team?</p><ul><li><p>Carefully review deliverables, milestones, and tasks.</p><p>Take the Plant pals project as an example. Before the project manager can refer to <em><strong>project charter</strong></em>, which we  set the goal, scope, and deliverables, etc. Then break down the deliverables to milestons, and break down these milestons to tasks so that we can assign these tasks to our team members.</p></li><li><p>Give yourself time to plan.</p><p>It’s a time-intensive process, especially for a huge project with multiple deliverables. Planning can give us a sense of what we can and cannot accomplish in a certain time.</p></li><li><p>Recognize and plan for the inevitable: things will go wrong.</p><p>Actually, you cannot make a list of all problems, but the team can identify the risks most likely to happen, and make a plan for these risks. Task and project buffer are needed.</p></li><li><p>Stay curious</p><p>Sit down and ask your teammate question again, again and again.</p></li><li><p>Champion your plan</p><p>Tell your team why it benefits them to stay on top of the plan. By doing so, you may influence your teammates to stay on track and update the plan regularly. </p></li></ul><h2 id="Creating-a-project-plan-Tools-and-templates"><a href="#Creating-a-project-plan-Tools-and-templates" class="headerlink" title="Creating a project plan: Tools and templates"></a>Creating a project plan: Tools and templates</h2><p>We have included links to some project plan templates below:</p><p><a class="link"   href="https://www.smartsheet.com/content/project-plan-templates" >Smartsheet: Project Plan Templates for Microsoft Word<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p><a class="link"   href="https://www.smartsheet.com/free-google-docs-templates-google-timeline-templates" >Smartsheet: Project Plan Templates for Google Sheets<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1TauRTFipsWDWGqaw6tmqJeknKhVI5IjR5jJvBfVzfGw/copy" >Google Project Plan Timeline Template<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p><a class="link"   href="https://templates.office.com/en-us/simple-gantt-chart-tm16400962" >Microsoft Gantt Chart Template<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p>Tools: Smartsheet, Asana, Jira, Trello, Notion.</p><h2 id="Kanban"><a href="#Kanban" class="headerlink" title="Kanban"></a>Kanban</h2><p>Kanban boards are used to:</p><ul><li>Give a quick visual understanding of work details and provide critical task information.</li><li>Facilitate handoffs between stakeholders, such as between development and testing resources or between team members who work on related tasks.</li><li>Help with capturing metrics and improving workflows.</li></ul><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/3.16mvffwhnn7g.png"                      alt="Image of a Kanban board with a column for to do, in progress, testing and done"                ></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Week2 Building a project plan part 3&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : &lt;a class=&quot;link&quot;   h</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Notes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>C3_W2_P2_Using estimation to set project timelines</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2021/11/27/C3-W2-P2-Using-estimation-to-set-project-timelines/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2021/11/27/C3-W2-P2-Using-estimation-to-set-project-timelines/</id>
    <published>2021-11-27T12:08:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-11-27T12:16:53.639Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em><strong><u>Notes: Week2 Building a project plan part 2</u></strong></em> </p><p><em><strong>Course link</strong></em> : <a class="link"   href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/project-planning-google/home/welcome" >Project Planning: Putting It All Together<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><h1 id="Using-estimation-to-set-project-timelines"><a href="#Using-estimation-to-set-project-timelines" class="headerlink" title="Using estimation to set project timelines"></a>Using estimation to set project timelines</h1><h2 id="Time-estimation"><a href="#Time-estimation" class="headerlink" title="Time estimation"></a>Time estimation</h2><ul><li><p>Time estimation: A predication of the amount of time required to complete a task.</p></li><li><p>Effort estimation: A predication of the amount and difficulty of active effort required to complete a task.</p><ul><li>What’s the diffenence: effort estimation is about the active time required to complete a task and time estimation is about the time to complete the whole task. For example, the time I write this note is about one hour(active time), but I should spend time on learning, watching the vedio, building my knowledge, and thinking the way how to write it, etc.    </li></ul></li><li><p>Unrealistic effort estiamtion: Happens when you underestimate the amount of time it will take to complete the task. Often, the culprit for under estimating effort is optimism. And listen, optimism is a wonderful trait for a project manager to possess. But too much optimism can lead you to overlook potential risks that could set your plans behind schedule. </p><ul><li><p>How to avoid unrealistic effort estimation?</p><p>Your teammates will have the most realistic understanding of the amount of work required to complete a task and should be able to provide you with the best estimate.</p><p>Asking the teammate assigned to the task for their estimate is likely to yield a more accurate estimation since they’ll have a deeper understanding of the work and the nuances of what’s required to complete the task.</p></li></ul></li><li><p>Buffer: Extra time added to the end of task or project to account for unexpected slowdown or delays in work progress.</p><ul><li><p>Task buffer: Extra time tacked on to a specific task.</p><p>Task buffers should be used primarily for tasks out of team’s control. For example, when my team needs to buy some materials, the time that good shipped from the vendor to my company may delay one or two days.Task buffers should be used more sparingly for tasks within the project team’s control.</p></li><li><p>Project buffer: Adding a buffer to every task could lengthen your project schedule unnecessarily, leaving you, your team, and your stakeholders with an unrealistic timeline. This is where project buffers come in handy. Project buffers differ from task buffers in that they provide extra time to the overall project schedule.</p></li></ul></li></ul><h2 id="Run-fast-pay-later-A-case-study-on-time-estimation"><a href="#Run-fast-pay-later-A-case-study-on-time-estimation" class="headerlink" title="Run fast, pay later: A case study on time estimation"></a><strong>Run fast, pay later: A case study on time estimation</strong></h2><p>Kendra just scored a project manager role on a new project. It was a highly competitive bid, and the company and Kendra are eager to do a great job.</p><p>Kendra realized immediately that the timeline for the project would be almost impossible to execute. However, this was the first big project she was asked to manage. Therefore, instead of letting management know about the project’s impossible timeline, Kendra kept quiet and was determined to make it work. She rushed through the planning phase to get the team moving since time was ticking towards the project completion date. Kendra created all of the planning documents without input from her team or other stakeholders, with the sole intention of reaching the deadline.</p><p>During the team meeting, Kendra presented her project plan to the team. Right away, team members expressed their concerns with the timeline. They felt like there wasn’t enough time to complete their work, and they worried that the timeline didn’t incorporate enough time for reviews. Kendra documented the team’s concerns, but instructed them to simply work faster and make it happen.</p><p>As the project went on, the project faced schedule delays and other issues due to rework, previously unaccounted for tasks, stressed team members, and concerned stakeholders. Ultimately, the project missed its deadline. Later, the company did a retrospective to determine where things went wrong, and Kendra learned a lot of important lessons.</p><h3 id="Analysis-of-the-case"><a href="#Analysis-of-the-case" class="headerlink" title="Analysis of the case:"></a>Analysis of the case:</h3><h4 id="Escalating-concerns"><a href="#Escalating-concerns" class="headerlink" title="Escalating concerns"></a><strong>Escalating concerns</strong></h4><p>Kendra realized the timeline is problematic at the beginning. Instead of communicating with team members and stakeholders, and sharing the info, she decided to keep the issue to herself. She moved fast to meet the timeline instead of slowing down and planning the project throughly.</p><h4 id="Working-carefully"><a href="#Working-carefully" class="headerlink" title="Working carefully"></a><strong>Working carefully</strong></h4><p>If Kendra had taken the time to work carefully through the planning process, she may have been able to build a more realistic project plan to deliver the best product to the customer. She might also have identified potential time-saving activities that could have helped her team meet the project deadline. Thorough and careful planning with her team could have helped Kendra identify problems and solutions in advance, such as:</p><ul><li><strong>Elimination of tasks</strong>. It is possible that all of the tasks initially listed didn’t need to be completed. There may have been unnecessary work added in, and the team could have completed the project without it.</li><li><strong>Increased team size</strong>. Kendra could have addressed the potential schedule risk by requesting more resources like team members and budget early on in the project rather than trying to execute without the necessary resources.</li><li><strong>Streamlining of activities</strong>. There may have been some tasks that could have been done in parallel, or at least not in sequential order.</li></ul><h4 id="Gathering-input-from-the-team"><a href="#Gathering-input-from-the-team" class="headerlink" title="Gathering input from the team"></a><strong>Gathering input from the team</strong></h4><p>Kendra should have brought together team members, peers, and management to help build and review her project plan, especially given the challenges of meeting the proposed project timeline. Kendra also didn’t take action to address the concerns of the team members who were responsible for completing the tasks within the estimated time. </p><h3 id="Scenario-Time-estimation"><a href="#Scenario-Time-estimation" class="headerlink" title="Scenario: Time estimation"></a>Scenario: Time estimation</h3><p>Consider the following scenario: You are to oversee the project for a new text book release for the fall semester. You’ve done something similar before, so you feel confident speaking with the stakeholders, project sponsor, and faculty director. You assure them the project will meet the 6-month deadline.</p><p>Around three months into the project, you notice that your writers consistently miss the writing deadlines you assign. Then you learn that a printer upgrade may delay printing the text books. Unfortunately, you forgot to include this delay in your time estimation. Now you have to tell the stakeholders that the project may not launch in time for fall. </p><p>What might you do differently next time to improve the outcome of this situation?</p><ul><li>Before the project launch, we should talk with the writer to get an accurate time to finish the task.</li><li>The printer upgrade is a task out of project team’s control, so task buffer should be taken into consideration. Additionally, when the project manager first learns about the printer issue, we should immediately update the time estimation and inform stakeholders.</li><li>The project manager can also look towards potential time saving activities, including: eliminate tasks, increase the team size to get more work done and meet the deadline, and streamline any of the activities in order to complete them in parallel with other tasks.</li><li>All-in-all, it’s important to perform time estimation, effort estimation, and add buffers to build realistic plans for reaching the project goal and ultimately, success!</li></ul><h2 id="Capacity-planning-and-the-critical-path"><a href="#Capacity-planning-and-the-critical-path" class="headerlink" title="Capacity planning and the critical path"></a>Capacity planning and the critical path</h2><h3 id="What-is-capacity-planning-and-critical-path"><a href="#What-is-capacity-planning-and-critical-path" class="headerlink" title="What is capacity planning and critical path"></a>What is capacity planning and critical path</h3><p>Capacity: the amount of work that the people or resources assigned to the project can reasonably complete in a set period of time. In short, A man can only do so much, so when assign work, try to take capacity into consideration.</p><p>Capacity planning: Capacity planning refers to the act of allocating people, and resources to project tasks. And determining whether or not you have the necessary resources required to complete the work on time.</p><p>Here is a delivery example, one company sets their goal to ship 1000 bags to 8 areas in 4 days, and one courier can finish one area even if he spends all-day on his work, so two courier are needed for this mission. The capacity planning is to ensure enough people and resources to the task. It’s important to have a clear tasks and milestone, and then here comes the critical path.</p><p>Critical path: the list of project milestones that you must reach in order to meet the project goal on schedule. As well as the mandatory tasks that contribute to the completion of each milestone. Your critical path includes the bare minimum number of tasks and milestones you need to reach your project goal. </p><p>Then what we should do is to go back to WBS and set estimates on how long it will take to finish these tasks, from when to when. </p><h3 id="What-may-affect-critical-path"><a href="#What-may-affect-critical-path" class="headerlink" title="What may affect critical path?"></a>What may affect critical path?</h3><ul><li><p>Identify which tasks can happen in parallel VS. which tasks can happen in sequentially.</p><p>Follow the delivery project. They have to hire two couriers before they ship these bags, so find tasks happened in sequentially can give priority to these tasks. At the same time, the company can push other tasks like mock up the design and test to develop a new website.</p></li><li><p>Determine which tasks have a fixed start date.</p><p>A fixed start date refers to the date on which you must start work on your task in order to achieve your goal. If you plan to start the ship on Tuesday, then maybe get all bags ready on Monday.</p></li><li><p>Determine which tasks have an early start date.</p></li><li><p>Identify if the task has a <em>float</em>. (also called slack) Float refers to the amount of time you can wait to begin a task before it impacts the project schedule, and threatens the project outcome. This helps identify what is not on your critical path. For instance, tasks on the critical path should have zero float, meaning there is no room for delays.  If you plan delivery on a specific date, then zero float for  this task.</p></li></ul><h3 id="Why-the-critical-path-is-critical"><a href="#Why-the-critical-path-is-critical" class="headerlink" title="Why the critical path is critical?"></a>Why the critical path is critical?</h3><p>The critical path helps you determine <em><strong>the essential tasks</strong></em> that need to be completed on your project to meet your end goal and <em><strong>how long each task will take</strong></em>. The critical path also provides a quick reference for critical tasks by revealing which tasks will impact your project completion date negatively if their scheduled finish dates are late or missed. A critical path can help you define the resources you need, your project baselines, and any flexibility you have in the schedule.</p><h3 id="How-to-create-a-critical-path"><a href="#How-to-create-a-critical-path" class="headerlink" title="How to create a critical path?"></a>How to create a critical path?</h3><p>Step 1: <strong>Capture all tasks</strong>.  Make a list of all tasks related to the project, you can refer to previous documents like <strong>WBS</strong>. Here is an exaple to build the structure of a house. </p><table><thead><tr><th align="left"><strong>Task</strong></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left">A) Excavation</td></tr><tr><td align="left">B) Foundation</td></tr><tr><td align="left">C) Framing</td></tr><tr><td align="left">D) Roof</td></tr><tr><td align="left">E) Plumbing</td></tr><tr><td align="left">F) Heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC)</td></tr><tr><td align="left">G) Electrical</td></tr><tr><td align="left">H) Insulation</td></tr><tr><td align="left">I) Drywall + Paint</td></tr><tr><td align="left">J) Flooring</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Step 2: <strong>Set dependencies</strong>. Figure out which tasks must be completed before other tasks can start. Some questions may help a lot.</p><ul><li>Which task needs to take place before this task?</li><li>Which task can be finished at the same time as this task?</li><li>Which task needs to happen right after this task?</li></ul><table><thead><tr><th align="left"><strong>Task</strong></th><th align="left"><strong>Dependency</strong></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left">A) Excavation</td><td align="left"></td></tr><tr><td align="left">B) Foundation</td><td align="left">A) Excavation</td></tr><tr><td align="left">C) Framing</td><td align="left">B) Foundation</td></tr><tr><td align="left">D) Roof</td><td align="left">C) Framing</td></tr><tr><td align="left">E) Plumbing</td><td align="left">C) Framing</td></tr><tr><td align="left">F) HVAC</td><td align="left">C) Framing</td></tr><tr><td align="left">G) Electrical</td><td align="left">C) Framing</td></tr><tr><td align="left">H) Insulation</td><td align="left">E) Plumbing, F) HVAC, G) Electrical</td></tr><tr><td align="left">I) Drywall + Paint</td><td align="left">H) Insulation</td></tr><tr><td align="left">J) Flooring</td><td align="left">I) Drywall + Paint</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Step 3: <strong>Create a network diagram</strong>. Visualize the critical path is by creating a <strong>network diagram</strong>.</p><ul><li>The path of the work from the start of the project (excavation) to the end of the project (flooring)</li><li>Which tasks can be performed in parallel (e.g., HVAC and plumbing) and in sequence (e.g., plumbing then insulation)</li><li>Which non-essential tasks are NOT on the critical path</li></ul><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/1.49mbhk3tswy.svg"                      alt="A network diagram showing the critical path of tasks for building a house"                ></p><p>Step 4: <strong>Make time estimate</strong>. Consult key stakeholders to get accurate time estimates for each task. And update the network diagram.</p><table><thead><tr><th align="left"><strong>Task</strong></th><th align="left"><strong>Duration</strong></th><th align="left"><strong>Dependency</strong></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left">A) Excavation</td><td align="left">1 Day</td><td align="left"></td></tr><tr><td align="left">B) Foundation</td><td align="left">3 Days</td><td align="left">A) Excavation</td></tr><tr><td align="left">C) Framing</td><td align="left">15 Days</td><td align="left">B) Foundation</td></tr><tr><td align="left">D) Roof</td><td align="left">3 Days</td><td align="left">C) Framing</td></tr><tr><td align="left">E) Plumbing</td><td align="left">4 Days</td><td align="left">C) Framing</td></tr><tr><td align="left">F) HVAC</td><td align="left">3 Days</td><td align="left">C) Framing</td></tr><tr><td align="left">G) Electrical</td><td align="left">3 Days</td><td align="left">C) Framing</td></tr><tr><td align="left">H) Insulation</td><td align="left">2 Days</td><td align="left">E) Plumbing, F) HVAC, G) Electrical</td></tr><tr><td align="left">I) Drywall + Paint</td><td align="left">15 Days</td><td align="left">H) Insulation</td></tr><tr><td align="left">J) Flooring</td><td align="left">7 Days</td><td align="left">I) Drywall + Paint</td></tr></tbody></table><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/2.4pykhvkncb60.svg"                      alt="A network diagram showing the critical path of tasks for building a house with the number of days to complete each task"                ></p><p>Step 5: <strong>Find the Critical Path</strong>.</p><p>You can also calculate the critical path using two common approaches: the <strong>forward pass</strong> and the <strong>backward pass</strong>. These techniques are useful if you are asked to identify the <strong>earliest and latest start dates</strong> (the earliest and latest dates on which you can begin working on a task) or the <strong>slack</strong> (the amount of time that task can be delayed past its earliest start date without delaying the project).</p><ul><li>The <strong>forward pass</strong> refers to when you start at the beginning of your project task list and add up the duration of the tasks on the critical path to the end of your project. When using this approach, start with the first task you have identified that needs to be completed before anything else can start. </li><li>The <strong>backward pass</strong> is the opposite—start with the final task or milestone and move backwards through your schedule to determine the shortest path to completion. When there is a hard deadline, working backwards can help you determine which tasks are actually critical. You may be able to cut some tasks—or complete them later—in order to meet your deadline. </li></ul><p>Further reading:</p><ul><li><a class="link"   href="https://www.workamajig.com/blog/critical-path-method" >How to Use the Critical Path Method for Complete Beginners<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></li><li><a class="link"   href="https://www.wrike.com/blog/critical-path-is-easy-as-123/" >Critical Path Method: A Project Management Essential<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></li></ul><h2 id="Getting-accurate-time-estimates-from-your-team"><a href="#Getting-accurate-time-estimates-from-your-team" class="headerlink" title="Getting accurate time estimates from your team"></a>Getting accurate time estimates from your team</h2><p>When you try to estimate the time for tasks, it is the stage to get all your team members in, by a two-way discussion, and you’ll need to tap into your soft skills to get the most accurate estimate from your team.</p><p>Soft skills: personal characteristics that help people work effectively with others.</p><p>Soft skills for accurate estimation:</p><ul><li><p>Asking the right questions</p><p>Ask open-ended questions. Take Office Green project as an example. You’ve discussed the design of the new website with your web designer, and you’d like to know how long it will take them to mock up designs for your review. </p><p>Can you complete the mock-ups in one week? (Close-ended question with answer yes or no) May ask the following questions to learn more about how they work and what they do.</p><ul><li><p>How long does it typically take you to mock up a website design like this one? </p></li><li><p>How complex are the steps to complete this task? </p></li><li><p>What are the risks associated with this task? And, </p></li><li><p>When do you think you can have this ready? </p></li></ul></li><li><p>Negotiating effectively</p><p>For example, let’s imagine that the website designer estimates it will take them two weeks to mock up the website design for review. But perhaps you were hoping that the estimate might be closer to one week. </p><p>To arrive at an estimate that works for both you and the designer, you might gently challenge the estimate by asking follow-up questions. Perhaps you’d ask if their estimate includes mocking up designs for multiple pages. If so, you might ask if the designer is able to share one or two pages with you sooner than their proposed deadline. </p><p>By asking questions, you can determine if their estimate is flexible, or if you need to bring in an additional designer to support the schedule. By negotiating effectively with your teammates, you can create a sense of shared ownership over the project outcomes and create a schedule that aligns with everyone’s workload.</p></li><li><p>Practicing empathy</p><p>When you’re discussing estimates with the team, you might practice empathy by asking each person about their workload, including work outside of your project and the overall work-life balance.You might also ask if they’ve scheduled vacation or leave during the duration of the project, or if there are crucial holidays in which they won’t be working. This can help you avoid assigning tasks when teammates are unable to complete them on time.</p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Notes: Week2 Building a project plan part 2&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : &lt;a class=&quot;li</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Notes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>C3_W2_P1_Getting started with a project plan</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2021/11/27/C3-W2-P1-Getting-started-with-a-project-plan/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2021/11/27/C3-W2-P1-Getting-started-with-a-project-plan/</id>
    <published>2021-11-27T11:55:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-11-27T12:07:39.864Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Week2-Building-a-project-plan-part-1"><a href="#Week2-Building-a-project-plan-part-1" class="headerlink" title="Week2 Building a project plan part 1"></a><em><strong><u>Week2 Building a project plan part 1</u></strong></em></h3><p><em><strong>Course link</strong></em> : <a class="link"   href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/project-planning-google/home/welcome" >Project Planning: Putting It All Together<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><h1 id="Getting-started-with-a-project-plan"><a href="#Getting-started-with-a-project-plan" class="headerlink" title="Getting started with a project plan"></a>Getting started with a project plan</h1><h2 id="Introduction-Building-a-project-plan"><a href="#Introduction-Building-a-project-plan" class="headerlink" title="Introduction: Building a project plan"></a>Introduction: Building a project plan</h2><p>What to target?</p><ul><li>Why it is necessary to create and manage a project plan.</li><li>Discuss the definition of a project plan, and we’ll learn what typically goes into one.</li><li>Share how to use time estimation methods to prevent project failure.</li><li>Examine tools and best practices you can use to build out a project plan. </li></ul><h3 id="What-is-a-project-plan"><a href="#What-is-a-project-plan" class="headerlink" title="What is a project plan?"></a>What is a project plan?</h3><p>Every project plan is a living artifact that serves as your team’s roadmap throughout the project. We have covered some common elements of project plans, including <em><strong>tasks, milestones, people, documentation, and time</strong></em>.</p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/image-20211030194135814.2nmhkwusbu8.png"                      style="zoom:50%;"                 ><h2 id="Project-scope-and-goals"><a href="#Project-scope-and-goals" class="headerlink" title="Project scope and goals"></a><strong>Project scope and goals</strong></h2><p>Both the project scope and goals will be captured initially in your <strong>project charter</strong>, the document that clearly defines the key details of your project. You can link your project charter in your project plan. Having details about the project’s scope and goals easily accessible can help remind your team of the objectives they are trying to accomplish and if anything is asked of them that goes beyond what was initially agreed upon in order to achieve those objectives. </p><h2 id="Work-Breakdown-Structure-WBS"><a href="#Work-Breakdown-Structure-WBS" class="headerlink" title="Work Breakdown Structure (WBS)"></a><strong>Work Breakdown Structure (WBS)</strong></h2><p>As a reminder, a <strong>Work Breakdown Structure</strong> is a tool that sorts the <em><strong>milestones and tasks</strong></em> of a project in a hierarchy, in the order they need to be completed.  The WBS is key to your project plan since it breaks the work down into more manageable pieces. In your project plan, the tasks should be visible in one place with clear descriptions, owners, and due dates. This will allow you and your team to understand who is responsible for which tasks and when each task is supposed to be completed. Your project plan should also contain detailed milestones and statuses related to these tasks, which will help you and your team members visualize project progress. </p><p>In addition to the WBS, further documentation—such as a RACI chart—will help define roles and responsibilities and would be useful to add to your project plan. Keeping this documentation stored or linked in one place is a best practice for transparency and effective communication.</p><h2 id="Budget"><a href="#Budget" class="headerlink" title="Budget"></a><strong>Budget</strong></h2><p>Throughout the life cycle of your project, the budget will need to be managed and monitored. The project budget is often linked to the project plan because it is heavily dependent on key elements of the project. Linking these components allows for smoother management and visibility. </p><p>Depending on the size of your project and your organization, you may not be the primary person responsible for managing the project budget. For instance, if your project is at a large organization and the funds are managed by another department, you may not have as much autonomy or insight into all of the budget elements. As a result, you may not be able to monitor the budget closely. If someone in another department is managing the budget, make sure to have regular check-ins with them to ensure that you are aware of how you are tracking.</p><h2 id="Management-plans"><a href="#Management-plans" class="headerlink" title="Management plans"></a><strong>Management plans</strong></h2><p>Management plans—such as the change management plan, risk management plan, and communication plan—are all integral to keeping a project organized and on track and should be linked in your project plan. These plans will be discussed in detail in the coming lessons of this course. </p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;Week2-Building-a-project-plan-part-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Week2-Building-a-project-plan-part-1&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Week2 Building a pro</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Notes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>C3_W1_P2_Defining tasks and milestones</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2021/11/14/C3-W1-P2-Defining-tasks-and-milestones/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2021/11/14/C3-W1-P2-Defining-tasks-and-milestones/</id>
    <published>2021-11-13T16:05:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-08-03T06:07:55.973Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><u><em><strong>Notes: Project planing: put it all together. Week 1</strong></em></u></p><p><em><strong>Course link</strong></em> : <a class="link"   href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/project-planning-google/home/welcome" >Project Planning: Putting It All Together<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><h1 id="Defining-tasks-and-milestones"><a href="#Defining-tasks-and-milestones" class="headerlink" title="Defining tasks and milestones"></a>Defining tasks and milestones</h1><h2 id="Understanding-tasks-and-milestones"><a href="#Understanding-tasks-and-milestones" class="headerlink" title="Understanding tasks and milestones"></a>Understanding tasks and milestones</h2><p>Milestone: an <em><strong>important point within the project schedule</strong></em> that indicates progress and usually signifies the completion of a deliverable or phase of the project.</p><p>Project task: <em><strong>an activity</strong></em> that needs to be accomplished within a set period of time.</p><p>The work of a project is broken down into many different tasks. In order to reach a milestone, my team must complete multiple tasks. For example, when we want to do a mid-term presentation about our project, tasks may include brainstorm, creating a PPT,  and practice then pre-record.Milestones and project tasks are interconnected. Tasks ladder up to milestones, which are crucial for project tracking.</p><h2 id="The-importance-of-setting-milestones"><a href="#The-importance-of-setting-milestones" class="headerlink" title="The importance of setting milestones"></a>The importance of setting milestones</h2><ul><li><em><strong>Setting milestons gives you a clear understanging of the amount of work your project will require.</strong></em> When break down the project into pieces of milestones, and then you may know the amount of tasks needed to be done. Actually, it’s much more easier to think, when conducting, we will know the true amount of work.</li><li><em><strong>Keep project on track.</strong></em></li><li><em><strong>Milestones help uncover areas where you might need to adjust scope, timelines, or resources to meet your goals.</strong></em> For example, if you realize that reaching a milestone will require more tasks than you’d anticipated, you might ask a stakeholder for permission to reduce the scope of the project and cut down on the number of tasks.</li><li><em><strong>Reaching milestones can seiously motivate your team, and illustrate real progress to your stakeholders.</strong></em> </li><li>Milestones also server as agreat check-in point to highlight your progress to <em><strong>stakeholders</strong></em>. Give them a clear view of what have been done and the progress is on time. Milestones must be completed on time and in sequential order</li></ul><h2 id="How-to-set-milestones"><a href="#How-to-set-milestones" class="headerlink" title="How to set milestones?"></a>How to set milestones?</h2><p><em><strong>The first step to setting a milestone is to evaluate your project as a whole.</strong></em> It helps to refer back to your project charter to remind yourself of the project goal. Then, make a list of what your team needs to do to achieve that goal.  Once you’ve determined your milestones, the next step is to assign each one a deadline. To get a good sense of timing, you can connect with teammates to discuss the tasks required to reach each milestone and get their estimates for how long these tasks will take. When you set deadlines for milestones, you will also want to consider the needs of your stakeholders.</p><h3 id="Set-tasks-to-identify-milestones"><a href="#Set-tasks-to-identify-milestones" class="headerlink" title="Set tasks to identify milestones"></a>Set tasks to identify milestones</h3><p>Setting tasks can help you clearly define milestones. You can do this in two ways:</p><ol><li><strong>Top-down scheduling:</strong> In this approach, the project manager lays out the higher-level milestones, then works to break down the effort into project tasks. The project manager works with their team to ensure that all tasks are captured.</li><li><strong>Bottom-up scheduling:</strong> In this approach, the project manager looks at all of the individual tasks that need to be completed and then rolls those tasks into manageable chunks that lead to a milestone. </li></ol><h3 id="Milestone-setting-pitfalls"><a href="#Milestone-setting-pitfalls" class="headerlink" title="Milestone-setting pitfalls"></a><strong>Milestone-setting pitfalls</strong></h3><p>Here are some things to avoid when setting milestones: </p><ul><li><strong>Don’t set too many milestones</strong>. When there are too many milestones, their importance is downplayed. And, if milestones are too small or too specific, you may end up with too many, making the project look much bigger than it really is to your team and stakeholders. </li><li><strong>Don’t mistake tasks for milestones</strong>. Remember that milestones should represent moments in time, and in order to map out how you will get to those moments, you need to assign smaller tasks to each milestone.</li><li><strong>Don’t list your milestones and tasks separately.</strong> Make sure that tasks and milestones can be visualized together in one place, such as a project plan. This will help ensure that you are hitting your deadlines and milestones. </li></ul><h2 id="Creating-a-work-breakdown-structure"><a href="#Creating-a-work-breakdown-structure" class="headerlink" title="Creating a work breakdown structure"></a>Creating a work breakdown structure</h2><h3 id="Work-Breakdown-Structure-WBS"><a href="#Work-Breakdown-Structure-WBS" class="headerlink" title="Work Breakdown Structure (WBS)"></a>Work Breakdown Structure (WBS)</h3><p>A tool that sorts the milestones and tasks of a project in a hierarchy, in the order they need to be completed.</p><p>It makes it easier to understand all of the essential project tasks, such as estimating costs, developing a schedule, assigning roles and responsibilities, and tracking progress. </p><p><img                       lazyload                     src="/images/loading.svg"                     data-src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AllenZhuer/image-hosting/master/images/image-20211029100339396.1ta218aruz40.png"                      alt="WBS"                ></p><ul><li><p><strong>Start with the high-level, overarching project picture. Brainstorm with your team to list the major deliverables and milestones.</strong> Example: Imagine you are planning a company event. Your major milestones might include categories like “secure venue,” “finalize guest logistics,” and “establish agenda.”</p></li><li><p><strong>Identify the tasks that need to be performed in order to meet those milestones.</strong> Example: You could break a milestone like “secure venue” down into tasks like “research venues,” “tour and decorate space,” “make down payment,” and so on. </p></li><li><p><strong>Examine those tasks and break them down further into sub-tasks.</strong> Example: You could break down a task like “tour and decorate space” further into sub-tasks like “organize decorating committee,” “purchase decorations,” “assign decorating responsibilities,” and so on. </p></li></ul><p>Tips:</p><ul><li>To assign tasks between two or more team members with the same roles, you might take into consideration each person’s familiarity with the tasks at hand.</li><li>When assigning tasks, you should also consider each teammate’s workload.</li><li>As the project manager, you will ensure that your teammates are clear on their assigned tasks. Tool: Asana</li><li>One less obvious benefit of assigning tasks is that it creates a sense of personal responsibility for members of the team.</li><li>8/80 rule: A work package should take no less than 8 hours, and also no more than 80 hours.</li></ul><p> Further Reading: <a class="link"   href="https://www.lucidchart.com/blog/how-to-create-a-work-breakdown-structure-and-why-you-should" >How to Create a Work Breakdown Structure and Why You Should<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p>Scenario:</p><p>As a project manager for Office Green, your job includes working with the operations team to develop and implement an Operations and Training plan. Your team will use this plan for ongoing maintenance of the Plant Pals service. It will take six months to fully implement all protocols, including setting up operational tools, putting delivery processes in place, and training employees. The project will begin before the Plant Pals launch and extend beyond it.</p><p>The Operations team is responsible for managing the organization’s day-to-day business so that it continues to run smoothly. Operations provides resources to other departments, ensures consistency, and maintains the company’s profitability. The Chief Operations Officer (COO) typically leads the Operations team and works closely with other divisions, such as Sales, Client Services, Human Resources, Information Technology (IT), as well as the project manager. </p><p>Developing the Operations and Training plan marks a new stage of the project, with its own set of goals and deliverables. After assessing the requirements for the plan you determine three major milestones:</p><ul><li><em><strong>Establish a plant delivery and logistics plan</strong></em></li><li><em><strong>Select and install supply chain management software and equipment</strong></em></li><li><em><strong>Develop and launch an employee training program</strong></em></li></ul><p>For each milestone, you divide the work into three separate tasks. Each task has its own owner, duration, and details. The tasks associated with your milestones include: </p><ul><li><strong>Establish a plant delivery and logistics plan</strong>: Team members will need to source materials for packaging and hire delivery drivers. They are also responsible for calculating the delivery fees. </li><li><strong>Select and install supply chain software and equipment</strong>: Team members will supervise vendor setup of inventory management and fulfillment software. They must also supervise vendor installation of fulfillment equipment and determine internal safety protocols for the equipment.</li><li><strong>Develop and launch an employee training program</strong>: Team members will need to develop training sessions, train employees to use the software and equipment, and monitor progress and improve training processes.</li></ul><p>My trial:</p><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/11ZFVH7-HgzbNIiKM_Y7OqxhbzVTh51lzGx8UOfJB8oo/edit#slide=id.p1" >Use a WBS to create project tasks and milestones - Part 1<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1fx8Nfa2c5S8oRhKYEw2_vZ4enxRSF-DdijcccmpWtE4/edit#gid=185434937" >Use a WBS to create milestones and project tasks - Part 2<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p>Google’ reference:</p><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1MPh9B1R4AIGjfTP24mn0LF5wPbQCEbWsT_-bKf_aBxc/edit?resourcekey=0-E9l5CNEj7B3oZ-RwseXyRA#slide=id.ge7313b124a_0_0" >WBS Brainstorm Diagram<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1DesMW3hmpzocK-wQqZQ-modRzSFJYyZOQTF49J23Q08/edit#gid=0" >Use a WBS to create milestones and project tasks - Part 2<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><p>The director recommend Asana as a tool to develop WBS, but not free for students outside the US right now. I think Notion can do the same thing, I will take a try.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes: Project planing: put it all together. Week 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : &lt;a cl</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Notes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>C3_W1_P1_Uderstanding the planning phase componets</title>
    <link href="http://example.com/2021/11/13/C3-W1-P1_Uderstanding-the-planning-phase-componets/"/>
    <id>http://example.com/2021/11/13/C3-W1-P1_Uderstanding-the-planning-phase-componets/</id>
    <published>2021-11-13T13:22:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-11-27T12:06:13.780Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><u><em><strong>Notes: Project planing: put it all together. Week 1</strong></em></u></p><p><em><strong>Course link</strong></em> : <a class="link"   href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/project-planning-google/home/welcome" >Project Planning: Putting It All Together<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><h1 id="Uderstanding-the-planning-phase-componets"><a href="#Uderstanding-the-planning-phase-componets" class="headerlink" title="Uderstanding the planning phase componets"></a>Uderstanding the planning phase componets</h1><h2 id="The-benefits-of-planning-a-project"><a href="#The-benefits-of-planning-a-project" class="headerlink" title="The benefits of planning a project"></a>The benefits of planning a project</h2><h3 id="when-should-plan-a-project"><a href="#when-should-plan-a-project" class="headerlink" title="when should plan a project ?"></a>when should plan a project ?</h3><ul><li>Project manager gets assigned</li><li>Project goals, scope, deliveries have been approved</li><li>Team members have been assigned</li><li>Sign off on your project charter</li></ul><h3 id="What-planning-a-project-can-help"><a href="#What-planning-a-project-can-help" class="headerlink" title="What planning a project can help ?"></a>What planning a project can help ?</h3><ul><li>Understanding the work needed to achieve your goals </li><li>Coordinate efforts and timelines with other teams, contractors, and vendors</li><li>Identify and prepare for risks</li><li>Get ‘Buy-in’ from key members of the project team</li><li>Demonstrates to stakeholders that the team is taking care to start the project with a detailed plan</li></ul><h2 id="Launching-the-planning-phase"><a href="#Launching-the-planning-phase" class="headerlink" title="Launching the planning phase"></a>Launching the planning phase</h2><h3 id="What-should-be-taken-into-consideration"><a href="#What-should-be-taken-into-consideration" class="headerlink" title="What should be taken into consideration?"></a>What should be taken into consideration?</h3><ul><li><p>Schedule</p><p>The project timeline, sheich includes the start date, the end date, and dates for events in between.</p></li><li><p>Budget</p><p>The budget accounts for the total cost to complete the project. The total cost needs to be broken down to determine how much has to be spent on different elements of the project. </p></li><li><p>Risk management</p><p>Searching for possible problems related to the project and plannning ahead to mitigate these risks.</p><p>Where might the schedule get off track?</p><p>Where might the budget exceed your estimates?</p></li></ul><h3 id="Scenario"><a href="#Scenario" class="headerlink" title="Scenario"></a>Scenario</h3><p>Imagine that you’re a project manager helping a restaurant owner launch an updated menu with a few new food items at 15 locations. The owner would like you to oversee the redesign of the menu and distribution to all locations. </p><p>You’re preparing for your project’s eventual kickoff meeting. Right now, you’re thinking through the three main planning activities: building the schedule, assessing the budget, and considering potential risks. </p><ul><li><p>Schedule: The dates may include important constraints from vendors, kickoffs dates, and when to complete certain tasks. Ande a target date for the product (menu) launch, and validate that with the client. While trying to stick to the schedule, it may change during the project.</p></li><li><p>Budget: </p><ul><li>Call vendors and get quotes of items you may need to purchase.</li><li>Fees to my team members.</li><li>Fees for outside consultants or service-based vendors.</li><li>If I want to launch a website to offer ordering service, fee to develop and operate the web should also be taken into consideration.</li><li>And if the project is delayed, then what it may affect my budget? </li></ul></li><li><p>Risk management:</p><ul><li>Budget items that are likely to increase in cost. The season, politics, and natural disasters can make a difference to my contractors.</li><li>Days-off or holiday. </li><li>If team members get sick.</li><li>What about tasks and deliverables that could delay the project? </li><li>Feedback from stakeholders could also cause delays.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 id="Facilitating-a-project-kick-off-meeting"><a href="#Facilitating-a-project-kick-off-meeting" class="headerlink" title="Facilitating a project kick-off meeting"></a>Facilitating a project kick-off meeting</h2><h3 id="What-is-a-project-kick-off-meeting"><a href="#What-is-a-project-kick-off-meeting" class="headerlink" title="What is a project kick-off meeting?"></a>What is a project kick-off meeting?</h3><p>A project kickoff meeting is the first meeting in which a project team comes together to ground everyone in a shared vision, <em><strong>gain a shared understanding of the project’s goals and scope</strong></em>, and to <em><strong>understand each person’s individual roles within the team</strong></em>.</p><h3 id="Who-to-invite"><a href="#Who-to-invite" class="headerlink" title="Who to invite?"></a>Who to invite?</h3><p><a class="link"   href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/18cXj5XW3FaXz_-I_cC3klzp0Hm1xJeWlrOxhXMFEXPE/edit#gid=1434934716" >RACI Chart<i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a></p><ul><li>Project team</li><li>Project stakeholders</li><li>Project sponsor</li></ul><h3 id="Why-I-need-a-kick-off-meeting"><a href="#Why-I-need-a-kick-off-meeting" class="headerlink" title="Why I need a kick-off meeting?"></a>Why I need a kick-off meeting?</h3><ul><li>Establish a shared vision</li><li>Align on scope</li><li>Build team rapport </li><li>Ask questions and offer insights</li><li>Set expectations</li></ul><p>The purpose of a kick-off meeting is to ground everyone in a shared vision, ensure they understand the project’s goals and scope, and make sure that they are all on the same page about their roles and responsibilities on the project. The kick-off meeting is critical to a project’s overall success. It gets the team together to align on goals and visions for the project and sets the project up for success.</p><h3 id="How-to-plan-a-kick-off-meeting"><a href="#How-to-plan-a-kick-off-meeting" class="headerlink" title="How to plan a kick-off meeting?"></a>How to plan a kick-off meeting?</h3><ul><li><p>Introductions</p><ul><li><p>Team member names</p></li><li><p>Project roles</p></li><li><p>Fun facts </p><p>===&gt; build team rapport</p></li></ul></li><li><p>Background </p><ul><li>How the project come to be </li><li>Why the project matters</li><li>Set a  shared vision</li></ul></li><li><p>Goals and scope</p><ul><li>In-scope</li><li>Out-of-scope</li><li>Target launch time</li><li>Milestones</li></ul></li><li><p>Roles: What work everyone is responsible for throughout the duration of the project</p></li><li><p>Collaboration</p><ul><li>Shared project tools and documents</li><li>Communication expectations e.g. daily email, weekly team check-in meeting</li></ul></li><li><p>What comes next : Set expectations and action items ==&gt; to make each teammate what actions they will need to take next.</p></li><li><p>Questions (put qs into a shared document)</p><ul><li>Gain clarity on meeting topics</li><li>Ensure the project benefits from diversity of thoughts experiences, and ideas</li></ul><p><u><em><strong>I am the man who help my teammates remove the roadblocks.</strong></em></u></p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes: Project planing: put it all together. Week 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; : &lt;a cl</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
    <category term="PM" scheme="http://example.com/tags/PM/"/>
    
    <category term="Notes" scheme="http://example.com/tags/Notes/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
